you need this skill if there's somebody
如果
in your life and you don't know whether
你生活中遇到某个人，你不知道
they're a snake or they're genuinely
他是阴险狡诈还是真心待你，你就需要这项技能。
your friend approach them from an angle
从某个角度接近他，出其不意地给
and surprise them and for a second you
他一个惊喜。在那一瞬间，你会
detect what we call you should become
察觉到我们所说的“你应该
aware of that Robert Green is one of the
意识到这一点”。罗伯特·格林是
bestselling authors in history he's an
史上最畅销的作家之一，他是
internationally renowned expert on power
国际知名的权力策略专家，
by Jay-Z Kanye West The Godfather of
Jay-Z 和 Kanye West 的歌曲中都曾引用过他的观点。他是
power seduction and Mastery we have this
权力、诱惑和掌控的教父。我们常常认为，
idea that if I apply myself really hard
只要我足够努力，就
I should be successful but I kept
应该成功。但我一直
noticing this blind spot that people had
注意到人们的盲点：
they were terrible in dealing with
他们不擅长与
people and if you're not careful and
人相处。如果你不小心，
constantly misreading people they could
总是误读别人，他们就会
manipulate you they can wound you but if
操纵你，伤害你。但如果
you follow the process that I lay out it
你遵循我提出的方法，这将
will be the best defense you could ever
是你一生中最强大的防御。
have in your life you know all the
你知道
tricks people are playing on you we have
人们都在耍什么花招，我们必须
to learn to look behind people's masks
学会看穿别人的面具。
being a human being means we lie but you
身为人类，我们都会说谎，但你
know what doesn't lie body language eyes
知道什么不会说谎吗？肢体语言，眼神
are hard lie the smile tells you a
很难说谎。
hundred different things if you know how
如果你懂得解读，微笑会告诉你一百种不同的信息。
to read it but the problem that you have
但你面临的问题是……
is you think it's a natural skill I'm a
如果你认为这是与生俱来的技能，我是
human being I know how to read people
个人，我知道如何读懂人心，而你
you don't you're operating in darkness
不知道，你只是在黑暗中摸索。
but I do believe everybody has that
但我相信每个人都有这种
potential so the first thing you do
潜力。所以，你首先要面对的
is Frenemies do we all have Frenemies
是“亦敌亦友”——我们都有这样的人吗？
yes they sabotage you hurt you and you
是的，他们会破坏你、伤害你，你
don't want them in your life and one
不想让他们出现在你的生活中。而“
common sign of a friend ofy is there
朋友”的一个常见特征就是……
it's absolutely crazy to me that so many
对我来说，
of you have decided to watch our show um
你们这么多人选择观看我们的节目，
subscribe to our show we now have five
订阅我们的节目，简直太不可思议了。我们现在
million subscribers on YouTube which is
在YouTube上有五百万订阅者，这个
a number that I just can't comprehend
数字我简直无法想象，这对我来说是
and it's a dream that I absolutely never
做梦都想不到的。
could have had we started the dire of a
我们三年前开始制作《Dire of a
CO just over three years ago now and in
CO》，
my wildest expectations we might have
我最乐观的预期是
had 100,000 subscribers by now so you
现在可能有十万订阅者。所以，你们
can imagine how shocked I am that so
可以想象我有多么震惊，这么
many of you have chosen to tune into
多人选择
these conversations every week um and
每周收看我们的节目，花
spend some time with us so thank you and
时间陪伴我们。谢谢你们！
I made a deal with you I made a deal
我和你们做了个约定，
that if you subscribe to the show that
如果你订阅……
we would continue to raise the bar and
我们一直致力于提升节目质量，
2024 we're going to raise the bar like
2024年我们将以前所未有的方式提升标准。过去
last nine months on a surprise for all
九个月，我一直在为所有订阅节目的朋友们准备一个惊喜，
and I'm very excited to deliver that for
我非常激动地要把它呈现给
you the production's going to change
大家。节目制作将会发生改变，
we're going to go even further with our
我们将与
guests and we're going to tell even more
嘉宾进行更深入的交流，讲述更多
Global stories so as always if you
全球故事。所以，和以往一样，如果您
appreciate what we're doing here simple
喜欢我们的节目，
free favor I'll ask from you is to hit
我唯一的请求就是点击
the Subscribe button let's get on with
订阅按钮。让我们开始今天的
[Music]
[音乐]
episode Robert you wrote a book about
节目吧。罗伯特，你在2018年写了一本关于
human nature in 2018 called the laws of
人性的书，叫做《人性的法则》。
nature why did you write that
你为什么写这
book well it's the fruit of a lot of
本书呢？
experiences that I've had um so I wrote
嗯，这本书是我很多经历的结晶。我写了《
the 48 Laws of Power and prior of that
权力的48条法则》，在那之前，
book I was somebody who never had any
我是一个
power in life I was sort of a failure
生活中没有任何权力的人，我算是失败者。
you know um I had gone through so many
我做过很多
different jobs and then all of a sudden
不同的工作，然后突然之间，
I write this one book and people are
我写了这本书，人们开始向
coming to me for advice it's kind of
我寻求建议。这感觉很奇妙。 令人
shocking right and I started noticing a
震惊，对吧？我开始注意到一个
trend and the trend is we live in this
趋势，那就是我们生活在一个
intense technological age where we have
科技高度发达的时代，
so much power at our finger tips right
触手可及的权力如此巨大，
and we it's so easy to get attention and
我们很容易就能获得关注
on and on and on and we have this idea
等等。我们有一种想法，
that everything in life should be easy
认为生活中的一切都应该轻而易举，
it's all about just well if I apply
只要我
myself really hard I should be
足够努力，就应该
successful but I kept noticing this
成功。但我一直注意到
blind spot that people had they were
人们的盲点：他们不
terrible in dealing with people they
擅长与人相处，犯了很多
were making all of these mistakes
错误。
everybody wears a mask you wear a mask I
每个人都戴着面具，你戴着面具，我也
wear a mask when we're out in the public
戴着面具。当我们身处公共
realm we don't exactly say what we think
场合时，我们不会直接说出自己的想法，对吧？
right we we're all a bit strategic and
我们都有些策略性。
if you're not careful you're constantly
如果你不小心，就会不断
saying the wrong things you're
说错话，
constantly misreading people you're
不断误读他人。你在
doing things at your job that you think
工作中做一些你认为
are going to impress but they have the
会给人留下深刻印象的事情，结果却
opposite effect and then something bad
适得其反。然后，糟糕的事情
happens and you're confused and you're
发生了，你感到困惑和
emotional it was like this circle
情绪低落。这就像一个
atmosphere of pain around the globe of
痛苦的循环，席卷全球，
people suffering because they don't know
人们都在受苦，因为他们不知道
how to handle the people in their lives
如何处理生活中的人，
and because we're so virtual and we're
因为我们太过虚拟，太过
so locked in our phones that we're
封闭。 我们越来越依赖手机，越来越不擅长
becoming worse and worse at Reading
读懂
other people at understanding them you
别人，越来越不擅长理解别人。你
know when I sitting across from you I
知道，当我坐在你对面时，我
can see your body language I can see
能看到你的肢体语言，能看到
your nonverbals I can see all sorts of
你的非语言信息，能看到各种各样的
things I can deal with you as a human
东西，我可以把你当成一个真正的人来对待。
but when I spend 95% of my time behind a
但是，当我95%的时间都花在屏幕后面，甚至连约会都是这样进行的，那么
date basic human skills of understanding
理解、沟通、同理心、读懂这些基本的人际交往能力
they're getting hopelessly degraded
正在迅速退化。这就是
that's my long-winded answer for why I
我
wrote that
写那
book if there's someone listening out
本书的缘由。如果有人正在听，
there and they can relate to certain
并且能理解我
parts of what you've just said maybe
刚才说的某些内容，也许是
it's a lack of their own self-awareness
他们缺乏自我认知，
or maybe they have poor sort of
或者他们对
awareness of others is there a starting
别人的认知很差。那么，有没有什么方法可以
place to reversing that is there maybe a
扭转这种局面？有没有什么
most important skill that we need to
最重要的技能是我们必须
master as at the foundation of that
掌握的，作为这种
transformation yeah it's very simple
转变的基础？其实很简单，就是
it's to get down on your hands and knees
放下身段，
and realize you're bad at dealing with
意识到自己不擅长与
people the problem that you have is you
人相处。你的问题在于你
think that it's a natural skill yeah I'm
认为这是一种与生俱来的技能。“是啊，我做得还行，
okay at it I just kind of wing it I
我只是有点……” 凭感觉？我
understand what I'm doing I'm a human
明白自己在做什么。我是个人，我，我，
being I I I I know how to read people
我知道如何识人等等。你
Etc you don't you're operating in
不懂，你就像在
darkness you're groping around just
黑暗中摸索，你只是在瞎转悠。
realize first of all that you need this
首先你要意识到你需要这项
skill and once you realize that the
技能。一旦你意识到这一点，
first thing you do is you look inward
第一件事就是反省自己，审视
you look at your own nature you look at
自己的本性，看看
the things that I write about in the
我在
book about
书中写的关于
narcissism about irrationality and
自恋和非理性行为的内容。
instead of searching for the people
与其在
around you that fit those categories
你周围寻找符合这些特征的人，不如审视你
look at yourself so it all begins with
自己。一切都始于
self-awareness you are the best subject
自我认知。​​你是人性的最佳研究对象。
of human nature so when I was writing
所以，当我写
this book it was actually quite painful
这本书的时候，其实相当痛苦。
so I'm writing a chapter on
我正在写关于
narcissism one of the longest chapters
自恋的章节，这是书中篇幅最长的章节之一，
in the book because it's a very
因为它是一个非常
important subject and I'm telling myself
重要的主题。我告诉自己：“
Robert you're quite a narcissist you
罗伯特，你其实很自恋。”你以前
didn't think of yourself that way but
并不这么认为，但
you have all of these classic tendencies
你确实具备
that you're writing about in the book it
你在书中写到的所有典型倾向。这很
was painful but in order to come to
痛苦，但为了
understand narcissism and other people I
理解自恋和其他人，我
had to sort of understand it in myself
不得不…… 理解自己内心的感受，
so step number one is I need this
所以第一步是：我需要这方面的
knowledge I'm actually not very good
知识。我其实不太擅长
with dealing with people it's caused me
与人相处，这给我带来了很多问题。
problems go back and review the problems
回顾一下
and the mistakes you've made mistakes
你犯过的错误，
I've made as well many many times and
我也犯过很多很多次。
then when you realize that you want this
当你意识到自己想要这方面的
knowledge then you begin by looking
知识时，就开始反省自己。
inward but if you think that that it's
但如果你觉得
not needed that you're not it's just oh
没必要，觉得只是“哦，
it's kind of interesting or maybe I'll
这有点意思”或者“也许我可以
sort of dabble in it it won't won't mean
浅尝辄止”，那对
anything to you you have to feel that
你来说毫无意义。你必须感受
pain that you've been through in life
生活中经历过的痛苦，这种
and it's kind of an ongoing pain it's
痛苦会持续存在，即使
one that I still have even though I
我
wrote the book where I misread people
写了那本书，我仍然感同身受。书中讲述了我误读他人，
where I inadvertently hurt them when I
无意中伤害了他们，而我
didn't mean to hurt them you know and I
并非有意如此。我依然能感受到这种痛苦，并为此感到痛苦。所以，
the pain that you feel the emotions that
你感受到的痛苦，以及由此产生的各种情绪，会
that this turns up motivate you then to
激励你
become better at understanding other
更好地理解
people what if you find things in
他人。如果你发现
yourself like you said that you don't
自己身上也有你不
like you find narcissism in yourself you
喜欢的东西，比如你发现自己有自恋倾向，那该怎么办？ 当你
find darkness in yourself what are we
发现自己内心深处的黑暗时，我们该如何面对
meant to do with that are we meant
它？是
to heal it resolve it you're meant to
治愈它、解决它，还是直面它、
look at it you're meant to confront it
直面它？
um I me I I have in the book a quote
嗯，我在书中引用了
from the great writer Anton Czech of
伟大作家安东·切赫的一句话：
that people can't begin to change
人们只有
themselves until they know who they are
了解自己、
until they understand themselves right
理解自己，才能开始改变自己。对吧？
so we all want to change we all want to
我们都想改变，都想
be better at ourselves but until we know
变得更好，但只有了解自己，才能
who we are until we realize our flaws
意识到自身的缺点
and our weaknesses so the main law of
和弱点。
human nature if I could summarize it is
如果要概括人性的主要规律，那就是
we don't like to look at ourselves it's
我们不喜欢审视自己，
always the other person they're the ones
总是把矛头指向别人——他们才是有问题的人，他们才是
are aggressive or passive aggressive
咄咄逼人或消极攻击的人，他们才是
they're the ones who feel Envy they're
嫉妒的人，他们才是理性的人。
the ones who are rational but me no no
但我呢？不不，
I'm a paragon of virtue I'm always moral
我是美德的化身，我总是道德高尚，我总是
I'm always good I'm always smart Etc so
善良，我总是聪明等等。所以，
it's the point isn't to beat yourself up
重点不是自责，也不是说“该死，
and go damn it I'm an awful human being
我是个糟糕的人”。
we're all humans come from the same
我们都是人类，都来自同一个
Source we all have the same ancestors
源头，我们都有相同的祖先，不是吗？
are we all have the same flaws in our
我们所有人的大脑都有同样的缺陷，
brain it's not like you're exceptional
你并不特殊，
it's not like you're the one person that
你也不是唯一一个没有自恋或自我中心的人。
have self-absorption so realizing that
所以，意识到
you're connected to all these people
你与所有人都有联系，
that we all have these flaws and
我们都有这些缺陷和
weaknesses is actually not a bad thing
弱点，这其实并不是一件坏事，而是
it's a good thing and then by examining
一件好事。然后，通过
yourself deeply you can begin to change
深入审视自己，你可以开始改变其中的
some of these things you know it's just
一些方面。你知道，就像
like you I don't go like oh damn it I'm
你一样，我不会突然意识到“哦，该死，我是个
a narcissist I'm I'm self-absorbed I
自恋狂，我太自我中心了，我
think a lot about myself I love talking
太爱想自己了，我喜欢谈论
about myself which is something I'm
自己——恐怕我确实
afraid I do like to do right the point
喜欢这样做。”重点
isn't well oh well I'm just depressed
不是“哦，好吧，我只是抑郁了，我
there nothing I can do once I'm aware of
无能为力”。一旦我意识到
it I can begin to change it but if I'm
这一点，我就可以开始改变它。但如果
always repressing if I'm always thinking
我总是压抑自己，总是想着“
no I'm good I don't have those problems
不，我很好，我没有这些问题”，
then if you can't see them how can you
那么如果你看不到它们，你怎么
change them how can you deal with them
能改变它们？你怎么能应对它们？
how can you be become a better person
你想成为一个更好的人吗？
how can you change those qualities that
如何改变那些
you don't want one of the most important
你不想要的特质？
things in the laws of human nature is
人性法则中最重要的一点是，
that you have patterns that you are
你有一些
compulsive it comes from your character
强迫性的模式。这些模式源于你的性格，比如
these patterns that you see in your
你在
Intimate Relationships you always fall
亲密关系中总是爱上
for the wrong person or you sometimes
错的人，或者有时会爱上错的
fall for the wrong person you see it in
人。在
your work world I make these mistakes I
工作中，你也会犯这些错误，
get fired for this reason etc etc and
因为这个原因被解雇等等。这些都是
they're good patterns but we tend to
好的模式，但我们往往会一遍又一遍地
repeat over and over and over again and
重复，这就是
these these s of compulsive Behavior
强迫行为。
being aware of these patterns being
意识到这些模式，
aware of these things you can now begin
意识到这些事情，你现在就可以开始
to you have the power to change
改变
them a lot of
它们了。很多
people climb the mountain of awareness
人都攀登上了觉察之山，
and they get I was thinking about people
他们……我一直在想
in my life that have climbed the
我生命中那些攀登过
mountain of awareness and in my own life
觉察之山的人，以及我自己生命中那些
hill things that I'm aware of Darkness
我意识到的事情，我意识到我内心的黑暗面，我
within me that I'm aware of or
意识到的
challenges or patterns I'm aware of
挑战或模式，以及我意识到的
taking the next step from so I think
下一步。所以我认为，
becoming aware is painful and then doing
意识到这些是痛苦的，然后采取行动
something about it is
是
difficult it's painful
困难的。痛苦是
because there's a lot of cognitive
因为在弄清楚这些事情的过程中会产生很多认知
dissonance associated with figuring out
失调。
that you're not who you want to be you
你知道，你并不是你想成为的人。
know and then doing something about it
而要改变现状，就
requires breaking what feels like old
需要打破
neurological Pathways in my brain you
大脑中那些看似陈旧的神经通路。你
know trigger you think about the Habit
知道，就像触发你思考习惯
cycle how breaking that is
循环一样，打破它有多么
difficult I look at it very differently
困难。恐怕我的看法截然不同。
I'm afraid so I think actually it's wor
所以，我认为
wor when you're not aware of who you are
当你不了解自己，
when you walk around in this world with
当你带着
all of these false ideas about who you
各种关于自己的错误观念在这个世界上行走时，这其实很糟糕。
are you you don't even know who you are
你甚至不知道自己是谁，
you're wearing this mask you're not
你戴着面具，你不真实，
as if you're somebody else and you're
你在世上表现得像另一个人，而你对此却浑然不觉。
not aware of that but it's causing you
但这正在给你带来
pain it's making you suffer because
痛苦，让你受苦，因为
you're not aware of of the real person
你不了解真正的自己，
that you are you're not authentic and
你不真实。
coming to terms with some of these dark
接受这些阴暗的
qualities is actually a very enlighten
特质实际上是一种非常开悟的
experience it's actually can be euphoric
体验，它甚至可以带来欣快感。你会意识到，我只是
you go I am an animal I'm not this saint
个动物，我不是圣人，
I'm not this Paragon that I thought I
我不是我以为的完美典范，
was I'm an animal with
我只是个有
flaws I can Embrace that we're all like
缺陷的动物，我可以接受这一点，我们都是如此，
that and it's a good thing and feeling
这是一件好事。 感觉
like you have this and you're coming to
自己拥有这种特质，并且正在逐渐接受
terms with it I have a chapter on the
它。我有一章专门讲
dark side of human nature everybody has
人性的阴暗面，每个人都有
a shadow side I have it you have it
阴暗面，我有，你也有，对吧？
right and seeing that shadow side which
看到
is something you've been repressing
你
since childhood and dealing with it and
从童年起就一直在压抑的阴暗面，去面对它，去处理它，去
confronting with it is actually one of
直面它，实际上是
the most wonderful experiences you can
你人生中最美好的经历之一，
have in life because repressing all of
因为压抑所有
these things is what is making you
这些特质才是让你
miserable in life but coming to terms
痛苦的根源。而接受真实的自己，意识到
with who you are and being aware of it
这一点，实际上是一种
is actually what liberating you know
解脱。你知道吗？我们所说的
where does it come from our Dark Side
阴暗面，
what you talk about in chapter nine of
你在第九章里提到的，是从哪里来的？
book well I think it comes from uh
我认为它源于
childhood
童年。
so when you're a child when you're three
当你还是个孩子，三
or four years old you're like this
四岁的时候，你就像一个
complete person I compare it to like
完整的人。我把它比作一个
this round ball you have good qualities
圆球，它有美好的品质，
you have loving qualities you love your
有爱的品质，你爱你的
parents perhaps you love your siblings
父母，也许爱你的兄弟姐妹，也许吧。
perhaps but you also have these other
但你也有一些
darker qualities these kind of
阴暗的特质，比如
aggressive impulses you sometimes you
攻击性的冲动。有时候你会
hit people sometimes you say nasty
打人，有时候你会说难听的话，对吧？
things right but you're a complete
但你是一个完整的
person it's natural it's who you are
人，这是自然的，这就是你，这就是
it's how you were born it's like a round
你与生俱来的样子。 它就像一个
ball and it's complete and then slowly
完整的圆球，然后
year by year month by month you have to
一年又一年，一个月又一个月地，你必须慢慢地
cut off that dark side that back side of
切断你内心黑暗的一面，切断
yours in school you're told don't ever
你内心深处的那一部分。在学校里，你被告知永远不要
show that part of you your parents are
展现你这一面。你的父母会说：“
come on you got to be nice you got to
拜托，你要友善，你要
get along we want want to be proud of
和睦相处，我们想为
you all of those aggressive impulses
你感到骄傲。”你所有的攻击性冲动，
that you have all of those feelings
你曾经感受到的所有情绪，你曾经对
somebody whatever you wish you had what
别人的嫉妒，你渴望拥有的东西，你
your your brother or sister had so they
兄弟姐妹拥有的东西，它们都被压抑了，对吧？
underground right you force them down
你强迫它们下去，
you don't want to deal with them but
你不想面对它们，但
they're still there because you're a
它们仍然存在，因为你是
human being those emotions don't leave
人。这些情绪不会离开
you they just get pushed down and they
你，它们只是被压抑，
go into the back side of your head that
进入你大脑的后半部分。那个
round ball now becomes cut off it's like
圆球现在被切断了，就像
the moon with a dark side and a front
月亮有正面和背面一样。
side and when you're out in the public
当你在公共场合、
and you're in work or in Social
工作或社交
situation you're only showing people
场合时，你只会向人们展示
that bright happy side the good side and
光明快乐的一面，
you're doing the damnedest to conceal
你竭尽全力地隐藏
all that dark energy inside of you and
你内心所有的黑暗能量。
then
然后
suddenly because you're not aware of it
突然之间，因为你没有意识到，它们就爆发了出来。
explosions very typical thing is you
爆发时，很典型的情况是你会
suddenly get angry and you burst out
突然生气，然后突然发出
with an angry email or you yell at
愤怒的邮件，或者对
somebody you say something kind of
某人大吼大叫，说一些
nasty and then you look back and you go
难听的话。之后你回头想想，这到底是从
where did that come from that I didn't
哪儿来的？
that's not really me I'm not really like
这不是我，我不是那样的人。
that I feel ashamed about that but what
我为此感到羞愧。但
you must realize is that's part of your
你必须意识到，那是你
Shadow that's speaking it's coming out
内心阴影的一部分在说话，它在释放，
you're just not aware of it you're
你只是没有意识到而已，你
trying to control it too much and I
试图控制它太多了。我
say the best thing in life to do is not
认为人生中最好的做法不是把
to take out this dark side and just
这种黑暗面暴露出来，到处散播，变得
nasty and aggressive that won't work but
恶毒和咄咄逼人，那样行不通。
you have to find ways to take that
你必须找到方法来利用这种
energy because that dark side contains a
能量，因为黑暗面蕴含着
lot of energy a lot of power and use it
巨大的能量和力量，你要用它，
and channel it into ways that are
引导它走向
productive so I happen to be someone who
积极的方向。我恰好是一个
has a fair amount of aggression I have
相当有攻击性的人，我必须
to admit I'm extremely competitive right
承认，我非常好胜，
even in card games I don't like losing
即使在玩纸牌游戏时，我也不喜欢输。
so I've channeled it into my books I
所以我把这种能量转化到了我的写作中，
take all of that energy and I put it
我把所有这些能量都投入
into making the best books that I can
到创作最好的书籍中。 我能
into ambition so if you're ambitious
理解雄心壮志，所以如果你雄心勃勃，就应该把
channeling that energy into becoming the
这种能量转化为成为最
best and beating the competition is is
优秀的人，击败竞争对手，这是
is a productive way of using that dark
一种有效利用这种负面
energy if you feel angry about a cause
能量的方式。如果你对某个事业
or something that pisses you off about
或
the world some injustices instead of
世界上的某些不公感到愤怒，与其抱怨，不如去做点什么，
involved in a movement or whatever you
参与到某个运动中，或者做任何能让你感到愤怒的事情，把
channel that energy into something
这种能量转化为
productive that's the way to deal with
有益的事情。这就是应对
the dark side and that's you can't go
阴暗面的方法。你不能一辈子都
throughout life imagining that you're
幻想自己是
the saint because you're not you have
圣人，因为你不是。你
qualities in your book about the
在书中谈到
strategies of war the second strategy of
战争策略时，也提到了这些品质。
War that you write about is do not fight
你写到的第二个战争策略是“不要打上一场
the last war and when I read that what I
战争”。我读到这句话时，
understood it to kind of mean was
理解它的意思是
about not being
不要
rigid you know how does one dismantle
固执己见。你知道，一个人该如何打破
their the prison of convention that they
自己身处的陈规陋习的牢笼？比如，
live in so for that lawyer or for that
那位律师，或者那位
person that's working in the financial
在金融
district who is you know 47 and they're
区工作的47岁律师或
a lawyer they're a a stock broker and
股票经纪人，
they're
他们很
miserable
痛苦，
um they have somewhat been imprisoned by
他们某种程度上是被困住了。
their own identity which is like a set
他们的身份认同就像一套
of ideas from the past and I'm really
来自过去的观念，我真的很
obsessed with how we get out of the way
着迷于我们如何摆脱这种身份
of our own identity so that we can live
认同的束缚，从而过上
our most fulfilling lives CU even me you
最充实的生活。你
know there's and probably even you I've
知道，即使是我，可能也包括你，我都
created this perception of who I am and
塑造了自己对“我是谁”的认知，
I'm like following the instructions
我每天都在按照这些认知行事。是的，
every day yeah it's a trap you you can't
这是一个陷阱，你不能
fall into that so one of the laws of
掉进去。我
power that I have one I think is very
拥有的权力法则之一，我认为非常
important I think it's l 25 or 26 I
重要，我想是第25或26条，我
don't remember the number is recreate
不记得具体数字了，那就是重塑
yourself
自我。
so the moment people start um uh know
当人们开始了解
who you are they they they they identify
你是谁，他们就会认同你，
they create your identity oh Robert
塑造你的身份认同。哦，罗伯特·
Green is this person who writes these
格林，就是那个写那些
dark Machiavellian manipulative books
黑暗、马基雅维利式、操纵人心的书的人，
then I'm trapped I'm trapped by their
那么我就被困住了，被他们对
perception of me and I always have to be
我的认知所困住，我总是像
like a little dog performing for them
一条小狗一样为他们表演。
right and I don't want to fall into that
我不想掉进这个
trap you have to recreate yourself you
陷阱，你必须重塑自我，你
have to use your personality and who you
必须把你的个性和真实的自我当作
are as clay that you are molding you're
黏土来塑造，你
like an AR artist and so you you change
就像一个艺术创作者。 你会
yourself for each person that's
根据每个人的情况改变自己，
different so for me it means I don't
所以对我来说，这意味着我不会
write 48 Laws of Power part two I write
写《权力的48条法则》第二部，而是写
now a book that's not like the 48 Laws
一本和《权力的48条法则》完全不同的书。
of Power at all for you it's doing your
对你来说，这意味着你可以继续做你的
podcast but changing it up or maybe you
播客，但要做出改变，或者你可以
do a different podcast or maybe you do
做一个不同的播客，或者你可以
go into a different career set maybe you
进入一个不同的职业领域，也许你会
become a a CEO or an entrepreneur in a
成为一名CEO，或者走一条
different direction I was recently on
不同的创业之路。我最近上了
Andrew hu huberman's podcast right one
安德鲁·胡伯曼的播客，对吧？他的播客是世界上
of the most successful podcasts besides
最成功的播客之一，和
yours in the world and
你的播客一样成功。
um he I don't want that's sound like
嗯，我不想听起来像是在
bragging but the book Mastery helped him
吹嘘，但《精通》这本书对他帮助
a lot because he was a professor I
很大，因为他曾经是
believe at Stanford I hope I have it
斯坦福大学的教授，我希望我没记错。
right everything was going well he was
一切都很顺利，他在
on a fast track in in Neuroscience but
神经科学领域前途光明，但
he was miserable he hated the
他很痛苦，他讨厌
politicking he hated all the [__]
政治，讨厌学术界所有那些乱七八糟的事情。
and then he read the book and he goes I
然后他读了这本书，他说——我
don't know how old he was he must have
不知道他当时多大，大概
been in his early 30s he goes I don't
30岁出头——他说：“我不想再这样下去了，
want to do this I want to change I want
我想……” 为了改变，我想
to recreate myself he decided to go into
重塑自我。他决定投身
podcasting to take all of his knowledge
播客行业，将他所有
about science and Neuroscience and bring
关于科学和神经科学的知识运用
it into a different medium and so that's
到一种不同的媒介中。这
that's extremely powerful because if he
非常强大，因为如果他
had stayed in
留在
Academia he would have gone down the
学术界，他就会走上
path that we're talking about it sounds
我们现在讨论的这条路。这听起来比
your 47 but being stuck in Academia when
47岁还在金融界工作要性感得多，但如果学术界
that is a path for misery if he doesn't
并不适合你，再加上大学里那些肮脏的政治斗争等等，那将是一条痛苦的道路。
fit so you have to kind of go through
所以你必须不断地经历
this process all the time and not let
这个过程，不要让
other people tell you who you
别人定义你
are in the case of Andrew huberman who
是谁。安德鲁·胡伯曼
transitioned from an academic to a
从学者转型为
podcaster it's Quite a feat because
播客主播，这确实是一项壮举，因为有
there's lots of forces that try and hold
很多力量试图维持
our existing identity in place
我们现有的身份。
a lot of people and to sort of cross the
很多人要跨越
chasm get past all of that force that
鸿沟，克服所有这些力量——“
says no we want you to stay with us
不，我们希望你留在我们身边，
Andrew we want you to be an academic who
安德鲁，我们希望你继续做学者，你
do you think you are being a podcaster
以为你做播客主播是什么身份？”——
you know that that that Force I'm so
你知道，那种力量…… 我很
intrigued by because everyone regardless
好奇，因为每个人，无论
of where they are now if they're going
他们现在身处何地，如果他们想要
to try and venture to somewhere else a
冒险前往一个
better place they're going to encounter
更好的地方，他们都会遇到这种情况。
that um how does one work through that
嗯，我们该如何克服它？那是什么？
what is that how do we understand that
我们该如何理解那股
Force that's trying to keep us down it
试图压制我们的力量？
usually happens when you're successful
通常，当你成功时，
that people start giving you these
人们会开始给你贴上各种
identities that kind of Define who you
标签，这些标签某种程度上定义了你
are and if you're okay with it that's
是谁。如果你接受这些标签，那很好；
fine you know if it doesn't but I'm a
如果你不接受，那就另当别论了。但我
big believer in listening to your own
坚信要倾听自己的
pain and listening to your own
痛苦和
frustration so when you feel frustrated
挫败感。所以，当你感到沮丧时，
in life you have to go through a process
你需要经历一个过程，
you have to look at it and you have to
你需要审视它，你需要
go what is the source of it normally the
找到它的根源。通常，
first thing you'll do is you'll blame
你首先会做的是……
other people you'll blame the world
你会责怪别人，你会责怪世界，
you'll blame your your spouse
你会责怪你的配偶、
your children whatever right and you
孩子等等，对吧？你
won't really look at what it is why
不会真正去审视
you're
自己
frustrated and if you look at it deeply
沮丧的根源。如果你深入思考，你会发现自己其实很
enough and you go I'm really frustrated
沮丧，
because I'm not enjoying my work I'm
因为我并不享受我的工作。我
making money I'm going there every day
挣钱，我每天都去上班，只是机械地重复着同样的动作。
I'm successful and people admire me but
我成功了，人们也欣赏我，但
I'm not happy I'm frustrated I'm upset
我并不快乐，我很沮丧，我很难过。
you've got to lean into that pain you've
你必须正视这种痛苦，你必须
got to lean lean into what frustrates
正视那些让
you and go go I can't go on another 5
你沮丧的事情，然后行动起来。我不能再这样持续五年了，
because the mind and the body are tied
因为身心是紧密相连的，它们
in there's no difference they're all
没有区别，它们都是一体的。我们都是
we're all one we're all a unity and so
一体的，我们是一个整体。所以，
when you start having these frustrations
当你开始感到沮丧，当
these desires that are not you're not
你的欲望没有得到满足时，就会
acting upon it creates physical problems
产生
you're not aware of why suddenly your
你意识不到的身体问题。比如，你的
blood pressure is rising why suddenly
血压突然升高，
your back is having pain like I'm having
你的背突然像我
right now it's all interconnected and
现在这样疼痛。这一切都是相互关联的。
when you're not doing something that you
当你…… 如果你不去做一些
that you're not engaged with your whole
你全身心投入的事情，你的整个身心就会
being goes out of whack everything
失衡，一切都会失灵。
doesn't work you've got to listen to it
你必须倾听内心的声音，
you've got to understand it and you've
你必须理解它，你必须行动起来。我渴望
excitement in my life I want a challenge
生活中的快乐和刺激，我渴望挑战。
it takes some fearlessness because
这需要一些勇气，因为
leaving a prestigious job at Stanford
离开斯坦福大学一份收入丰厚的知名工作——
where you've got money I don't know if
我不知道他是否
you had tenure or not or perhaps he did
拥有终身教职——
you know it takes some guts because
这需要一些胆量，因为
you're leaving something that that
你要离开一些
convention that's stable etc etc but
稳定、循规蹈矩的东西，等等等等。但
you've got to go it's not worth the
你必须离开，它不值得付出这样的
price it's not who I am I'm going to
代价，它不符合我的本性，将来我会为此付出代价。
suffer for it down the road and so you
所以，假设
know let's say he decided to go into
他决定去做
podcasting and it failed all right so be
播客，结果失败了，好吧，那就这样吧。
it then he learns that and he he's
他从中吸取了教训。他
somebody who's very smart he would have
非常聪明，
direction to go in if my book the 48
如果我的书《
Laws of Power hadn't been a success I
权力的48条法则》没有成功，我
don't know what would have happened to
不知道会发生什么，
me but hopefully I would have figured
但我希望……
out another way to go you know CU I also
你知道，我本来可以找到另一条路的。我也
had to drop a career direction that I
不得不放弃我原本的职业方向，
was going in but you've got to try
但你必须尝试，
you've got to be able to try and you've
你必须有能力去尝试，你必须
got to go say
告诉
yourself it's actually a great thing in
自己，这其实是件很棒的事。比如说，在
your 30s let's say to go I need
30多岁的时候，你可以说：“我需要一些
something new I need something
新的东西，我需要一些
completely different I need a new
完全不同的东西，我需要一个新的
challenge I'm going to drop this I'm
挑战。我要放弃这个，我要
going to start something you won't
开始一些新的东西。”你不会
believe the energy that will suddenly
相信你会突然
rise up you right you'll suddenly feel
涌起一股怎样的能量，你会突然感到
invigor you suddenly feel youthful again
活力四射，你会突然感觉自己又年轻了。
I'm not stuck in this thing I can try
我不会再困在这件事里了，我可以尝试
something else I'm so intrigued by two
其他的事情。我对其中两件事非常感兴趣，其中
things within that one of them was going
一件是回到
back to the case of Andrew who left
安德鲁的例子，他离开了
Stanford and became a podcaster was my
斯坦福大学，成为了一名播客主持人。我的
brain you said um he's an intelligent
大脑会说，嗯，他是个聪明
guy he would have figured it out if he'd
人，即使失败了，他也能找到出路。但
failed my brain also was saying he could
我的大脑也会说，他
have always gone back and there's a real
随时都可以回去。
illusion sometimes I think in most of
有时候，我认为在
our lives where we don't realize that if
我们的生活中，存在一种真正的错觉，那就是我们没有意识到，如果
we mess up and this thing as I think
我们搞砸了，就像
Jeff Bezos calls it this is probably a
杰夫·贝佐斯所说的那样…… 这大概属于
type two decision where we can walk back
第二类决策，我们可以随时回头，
through the door but it's this sort of
但正是这种“
something great if we fail that stops us
失败就会失去很多东西”的错觉阻止了我们
taking that first step and the other
迈出第一步。
thing I was curious about is this idea
我好奇的另一点是，
that pain is is a catalyst for Change
痛苦是改变的催化剂这种说法，人们是否必须经历那种“我受够了”的人生阶段才会改变？
sick of this to change can someone
有人能在经历那种阶段
change before they get
之前就改变吗？很
there unfortunately not sometimes the
遗憾，并非如此。有时候，
bottom has to drop out before you
你必须跌入谷底才能
realize what you really want and what
意识到自己真正想要什么，
you really you know need to get in life
真正需要什么。
uh I wish it weren't that way but um
唉，我希望事情不是这样，但那种
feeling like you're suffering and that
感觉——感觉自己正在受苦，感觉自己
you need a change and that if you go on
需要改变，感觉如果继续
this way bad things are going to happen
这样下去就会发生糟糕的事情——才是
is the greatest motivator of all because
最大的动力。因为
if you're moderately discontented with
如果你对工作只是略感不满，
your job you're going to constantly be
你就会不断地
justifying to yourself going uh it's all
自我安慰：“
right it'll get better I'll get there'll
没关系，情况会好转的，我会成功的，会有
be a new boss or I can always move from
新的老板，或者我可以跳槽
this job to another company similar
到另一家公司。”
you'll justify you'll never get out of
你会这样安慰自己，但你永远也无法摆脱困境。
it and the trap will just close in on
陷阱会慢慢收紧，
you and you'll never get out of it right
你永远也逃不掉，对吧？
it's those moments Where damn it I hate
就是那种时刻，你会想：该死，我讨厌
this I can't go on you know I'm I'm
这样，我坚持不下去了。你知道吗？我感觉自己快要
heading to Suicide I'm heading to
崩溃了，快要
depression I'm heading to drinking I'm
抑郁了，快要酗酒了，我
hitting bottom I don't like where I'm
跌入了谷底。我不喜欢我现在的处境。当然，也不用
going it doesn't have to be quite so
那么
drastic I know I'm exaggerating but you
极端，我知道我有点夸张，但你
have to feel a degree of pain and
必须感受到一定程度的痛苦和
frustration to say I need to make a
挫败感，才会意识到自己需要做出
major change in my life you know the
重大改变。你知道吗？还有一点，在
is in the same book you were quoting in
你刚才引用的那本书里，
the in in about Warfare I have What's
关于战争的部分，我提到了一种
called the death ground
叫做“死亡地带
strategy where you feel like so he's
策略”的东西。比如，他要开始做
going into podcasting and if you go in
播客，如果你抱着“
with the attitude well if I fail I'll
如果失败了，我就赶紧
just go scurrying back to Stanford
回斯坦福”的想法，
that's a recipe for failure in itself
那本身就是失败的预兆。
already your attitude is already half
你的态度已经一半是消极的，
fast you're already half into it you go
一半是消极的，你会对
to yourself I've got to I'm cutting my
自己说：“我必须这么做，
ties at Stanford if this podcast doesn't
如果这个播客失败了，
work I'm not going back it gives you the
我就不回去了。”这种想法会给你带来
energy the motivation the desire to
动力。 动力和渴望是
actually make it successful but if
真心想成功的，但如果
you're always going through life kind of
你总是
with half measures going well if I start
半途而废，想着“如果我
this business and it fails I'll go back
创业失败了，我就回
to living with my parents and and I'll
父母家住，再
and I'll do this other job you're not
去做另一份工作”，你就不会
going to put your full energy into it
全力以赴，也
you're not going to give all of yourself
不会全身心投入，结果很可能
fail it's really um it's so
失败。这真是太对了。
true um it reminded me of something I
这让我想起我在
was reading in one of the psychology
一本心理学
journals about a study they did with
期刊上读到的一项研究，研究人员让
participants where they asked them to do
参与者完成
a puzzle and offered them a delicious
一个拼图游戏，并提供美味的
snack as the reward and then in one
零食作为奖励。其中一
group they said um this is the only way
组参与者被告知，只有
to get the snack if you do this puzzle
完成这个拼图游戏才能获得零食；而
and then in the other group they said by
另一组参与者则被告知，走廊尽头的自动售货机里
the way the same snack is also available
也有同样的零食。结果发现，
then the people in the second group
第二组参与者因为
where they had a plan B were less
有了备选方案，所以
committed to doing the puzzle spent less
完成拼图游戏的投入度更低，花在拼图上的
time trying to solve it and did worse in
时间更少，最终成绩也更差。
the puzzle and it's this idea that a
这说明，备选方案
plan B actually psychologically does
实际上会
distract you from your plan a yeah we're
分散你对主要方案的注意力。 我们都是
we're animals right we have we have a
动物，对吧？我们有
certain nature which is what I talk
某种天性，这就是我在谈到
nature and our our earliest ancestors to
人性以及我们最早的祖先时所谈到的。
go back to something I was talking about
追溯到我刚才提到的，
our Brilliance the power of our species
我们物种的智慧和力量在于，与
compared to like chimpanzees and
黑猩猩、
cheetahs and lions etc etc but we use
猎豹、狮子等等相比，我们的体格其实非常虚弱。但我们运用
our brain and feeling the necessity
大脑，感受到
feeling that we're going to die unless
生存的必要性——如果
we don't solve these problems right if
我们不解决这些问题，
we don't use our birs if we don't create
如果我们不创造
tools if we don't work together as a
工具，如果我们不
team we're going to we're going to we're
团队合作，我们就会
going to die we won't survive is what
死。正是这种必要性激发了
makes us inventive it's what makes us
我们的创造力，让我们变得富有
creative it's almost like a barometric
创造力。这就像气压一样，
pressure I like that's the metaphor I
我
like to use what's that when you feel
喜欢用这个比喻。当你感受到
that pressure inside of you and it's
体内的那种压力，
very heavy like in like weather that's
非常沉重，就像天气非常
very you know heavy and thick You're
糟糕、非常闷热时，你会受到
motivated you feel it I've got to get up
激励，你会感觉到“我必须起床，我必须
in the morning I've got to do this I've
做这件事，我必须
got to accomplish this when that
完成这件事”。
pressure goes away and and you don't
压力消失了，你
feel any pressure in your life you can
感觉不到生活中的任何压力，你可以
do anything and there's no consequences
做任何事，而且没有任何后果，
for it you'll just waste time you'll
你只会浪费时间，
waste Years you'll waste months you'll
浪费数年，浪费数月，你永远
never accomplish anything you give
不会有所成就。你给
somebody a dead line right they'll
别人设定一个截止日期，他们
accomplish in two months what it would
两个月就能完成
take somebody two years to do without a
别人没有截止日期需要两年才能完成的事情。正是这种
deadline it's that necessity it's that
必要性，这种“
back I've got to get it done it makes
背后有把剑，我必须完成它”的感觉，让你把
you get things done it gives you the
事情做好，给你
energy it's get rich or die trying to
能量，就像“要么致富，要么死”一样。
quote somebody yeah you talk about that
引用某人的话，是的，你
in the Strate um the book about the
在《战略》这本书里也谈到了这一点。那本书是关于
strategies of war the chapter four or
战争战略的，第四章或者说
strategy number four is about creating a
第四个战略是关于营造
sense of urgency and Desperation
紧迫感和绝望感。
and when I was reading that I was
当我读到那一章时，我
thinking to be fair I don't know any
想，公平地说，我认识的
great leader that isn't a little bit
伟大领导者中，没有一个不带一点
urgent and a little bit desperate and
紧迫感和绝望感的。
even if they Fain that desperation to
即使他们假装绝望是为了
Galvanize people there's something about
激励人们，
creating urgency and Desperation in your
在生活中营造紧迫感和绝望感也具有
life that is incredible Tailwind is
不可思议的力量。顺风，
there any practical ways that you think
你认为有什么切实可行的方法吗？
the average person can create a a the
普通人可以
required sense of urgency in their life
在生活中营造一种必要的紧迫感，
so they can get things done well it's
从而把事情做好。
kind of like a level here so you need
这就像一个层级，你需要
challenges in your life that's what
挑战，这就是所谓的“
that's sort of what the death ground is
死亡地带”。你面临挑战，就必须迎难而上。
up to it if the challenge is too great
如果挑战太大，比如
if you're like I'm I'm
你
24 and I've never written a book but I'm
24岁，从未写过书，但你却想
going to write the best book ever you're
写出有史以来最棒的书，那
you're going to fail because it's too
你注定会失败，因为这对
far above you you're never going to
你来说太难了，你永远无法
reach it if it's too low you're never
企及。如果挑战太容易，你永远没有足够的
going to have the energy it's too easy
精力，因为它太简单了，
it's not going to motivate you but
无法激励你。但挑战
there's a sweet spot I don't know I'm
存在一个最佳平衡点，我不知道该怎么形容，我
just you know just drawing it here be
只是把它画在这里，
like here where it's a challenge it's
就像这样：挑战
above what you're can do can do right
高于你
now it's not so far above that you can't
现在的能力，但又不至于让你完全无法
possibly do it but it's enough of a
完成，而是足够具
challenge to mean God I better get my
有挑战性，让你意识到“天哪，我得振作起来， ...
together I better you know change my
你知道，改变我的
habits I've got to get up earlier I've
习惯，我得早起，我
got to work harder it's not like I have
得更努力。这并不是说我必须凌晨
to get up at 4 and force myself and work
四点就起床强迫自己锻炼
out Etc I can get up at 6 6:30 an hour
等等。我可以提前一个小时，六点或六点半起床，
earlier and I'm going to meet this
然后迎接这个
challenge that's a little bit above my
稍微超出我能力
level that's a powerful way of
范围的挑战。这是一种强大的
motivating yourself you need challenges
自我激励方式。你需要挑战，
you need constant challenges in life or
你需要生活中不断的挑战，否则
you're going to or you're going to
你就会
stagnate it's just the law of nature you
停滞不前，这是自然规律。你也
talk about false purpose as well yeah
谈到了虚假的目标，是的，
what is false purpose and how do we know
什么是虚假的目标？我们如何
the difference your purpose in life is
区分它们？你的人生目标是
something that you're born with it's
与生俱来的，
like your destiny this is what you were
就像你的命运，这是你注定要
meant to accomplish this was what you
完成的事情，这是你注定要成为的人，这是你注定要做的事情。
do and we were going through we were
我们之前讨论过，我们谈到了
talking about that in terms of your
你的
childhood Etc right but we humans are
童年等等，对吧？但我们人类
not born with that purpose engraved in
并非生来就带着刻在
our heads we don't wake up when we're
脑海里的使命感。我们不会
seven and go that's my purpose if it
七岁醒来就说“这就是我的使命”。如果真
were that easy it would be that simple
那么容易，那就简单多了，对吧？
right but because we don't have any
但事实并非如此。
direction you know animals don't wake up
你知道，我们没有方向。动物（
in the morning if they're not nocturnal
如果不是夜行动物）早上醒来不会想“
and go what am I going to do today I can
我今天要做什么？我可以
go here I can hunt for this anal I can
去这里，我可以猎捕这个，我可以捕猎那个，
un for that animal I could eat this no
我可以吃这个”。不，
they don't they operate by Instinct they
它们不会，它们凭本能行事，它们
don't they have a purpose it's it's
没有目标，它们的行为
almost okay we don't have that we have
几乎是自动的。我们没有这种目标，我们必须
to find our purpose and because it's so
找到自己的目标。因为目标如此
deep and and so important that if we
深刻，如此重要，如果我们
don't find it through this authentic
无法通过我所说的这种真实的过程找到它，
process I'm talking about we'll find it
我们就会从其他地方找到它，
somewhere else because we need a purpose
因为我们需要
in life we need something to live for
人生的目标，我们需要为之而活的东西。那会是什么呢？是
what will that be it will be drugs it
毒品？是
will be some kind of cult that I have to
某种我必须
join it will be some kind of political
加入的邪教？是某种
movement where I can get out all of my
我可以发泄所有
anger and vent all of my frustrations
愤怒、宣泄所有挫败感的政治运动？
you know it'll be on and on and on it's
你知道，它会没完没了。它
something that has nothing to do with
与
who you are personally but it's
你个人无关，但它是
something that you can believe in and
你可以相信的东西，
can give you a sense of purpose but it's
可以给你一种目标感，但它
not really who you are it's like a drug
并不是真正的你。 这就像毒品一样，
it's drugging you into believing that
它让你相信
you have a purpose but it's not the real
自己有使命感，但这并非
purpose that you were born for that's
你生来真正的使命。这就是
what I mean by false purpose and when we
我所说的虚假使命感。当我们
find our purpose if we are able to and
找到自己的使命感时——如果我们能够并且足够
lucky enough to discover
幸运地发现
it what's the variance in what someone's
它——你会发现，
capable of that's found their P purpose
找到使命感的人和
versus someone that hasn't do you think
没有找到使命感的人之间，能力上的差异有多大？想想看，
like what's the difference in how they
他们在
show up how they deliver the results
展现自我、取得成果、
they create the impact they
创造影响力方面有什么不同？
have when you find your
当你找到
purpose it's like everything falls into
使命感时，一切都会
place right you don't need to you don't
水到渠成，对吧？你
need to almost do anything you'll find
几乎不需要做什么，你会找到
whatever you need to find thing good
你需要的一切，美好的
things will come to you I know that
事物会降临到你身上。我知道这听起来很玄乎，很
mystical but I definitely believe it
神秘，但我坚信这一点。
right and so it's not like you have to
所以，这并不意味着你必须
try so hard yes you have to learn skills
非常努力。是的，你必须学习技能，
yes you have to apply yourself yes you
你必须全身心投入，你
have to work hard etc etc etc but things
必须努力工作等等等等，但当
just go so much more smoothly when you
你
have it so for instance one thing that
拥有使命感时，一切都会变得更加顺畅。例如，
happens when you have a sense of purpose
当你拥有使命感时，会发生一件事——
and I hate it's something that I feels
我讨厌这一点——那就是…… 我感觉……
um so I I know my narcissism is coming
嗯，我知道我的自恋又出来了……
out again um I know what I don't want
嗯，我知道我不想要什么，
that's you don't know the power of that
你不知道那种力量有多强大，
you can't imagine how powerful that is
你无法想象它有多强大。
so people come to me all the time with
所以人们总是跟我说：“
Robert we can make a lot of money doing
罗伯特，我们可以靠这个赚很多钱，
this we could try this we could let's
我们可以试试这个，我们可以把《
Power let's do this let's do that let's
权力的48条法则》拍成电视节目，我们做这个，我们做那个，我们
make a game I'm not interested it's not
做个游戏。” 我不感兴趣，这不是
my purpose no I don't want it if I
我的目标，不，我不想那样。如果我
didn't have that radar I'd be spreading
没有那种“雷达”，我就会分散精力
myself out into eight different venues
到八个不同的地方，
and I'd be you know all of my energy
你知道，我的所有精力都会
would be would be scattered I wouldn't
分散，我会失去
have that focus and I'd probably end up
专注力，最终可能会
being pretty miserable because I would
非常痛苦，因为我会
have lost my purpose but when you have a
失去目标。但是当你有了
sense of purpose it's like no I don't
目标感，你就会想：不，我不想做那个，我不想
want to do that I don't want to do that
做那个，
I don't want to I want to do this yeah
我不想，我想做这个。是的，
it can be rigid you have to be a little
它可能会很僵化，你必须
bit flexible so if somebody comes to me
灵活一些。所以如果有人来找我…… 我
and goes Robert what about this I'm open
和罗伯特说：“这个怎么样？我持开放态度，
to it that sounds moderately interesting
听起来有点意思。
all right maybe I'll try it you know and
好吧，也许我会试试。”你知道，
I and I do open things things like that
我确实对各种事情持开放态度。比如，
I'm going to be doing in a month I'm
一个月后，我要
recording uh a French version of you
录制一个法语版的大师班，你
know the master class there's a French
知道，那个大师班有法语版。
version of that so you know I'm not so
所以你知道，我不是那种只会写书的
rigid where I can only write books I can
死板模式，我可以
try other things because I can see value
尝试其他事情，因为我看到了它们的价值，
in it and it interests me it's a
也对它们感兴趣。
challenge being able to say no is so
能够说“不”是一种挑战，这非常
important and and it's so empowering and
重要，也非常有力量。这就是
that's what a sets of purpose will give
目标能带给
you to among other things there's a
你的东西。有一句
quote that says something
名言说，
like distractions come dressed up as
干扰常常伪装成
opportunities and to even know what a
机会。要弄清楚什么是干扰，
distraction is you first must understand
你首先必须明白
what your goal and what your purpose is
你的目标和目的是什么，
or else it's impossible to distinguish
否则就无法区分
between a distraction Robert go let's go
干扰和机会。罗伯特，我们开始吧，
start a game or an opportunity which is
开始游戏。这听起来
sounds much more like that Mastermind
更像是“智囊团”之类的节目。
thing and I think about this all the
我一直在思考这个问题，
time you know the more clear I am on the
你知道，我对
goal and what my purpose is the much
目标和目的越清晰，就越
easier it is to understand what a
容易理解……
distraction is for
分散注意力是因为
they do look the same when they my yes
他们看起来确实一样，是的，嗯，
well the other thing I do is I kind of
我做的另一件事是我会事先
game it
设想
out so somebody comes to me they go
一下。比如有人来找我说，我们来
let's do a television show the 48 Laws
做个电视节目，叫《权力的48条法则》吧。
of Power and believe me I've been
相信我，我已经经历过
through that about 85 times people
大约85次这样的事情了，有人
comeing to be that and we have even
来找我，我们甚至
attempted it but I go I've worked in
尝试过。但我说，我在好莱坞工作过，在
before before I had my books I know the
我出书之前就做过电视，我知道这个
process I know how miserable it can be I
过程，我知道它有多痛苦，我
know how you have no power I'm a writer
知道你没有权力。我现在是个作家，
now where I write books and I have all
我写书，我拥有所有的
the power I have all the
权力，我拥有所有的
control you go into Hollywood you go
控制权。你去好莱坞，去
into television or film 85 you know 800
电视或电影行业，你知道，85，800
other people join in and they all have
个人加入进来，他们都有
their ideas and they change this that
自己的想法，他们会改变一切，
you have no power and and it's meetings
你没有权力，然后就是没完没了的会议，没完没了的谈话。
talk talk talk I game it out and I go I
我会事先设想一下，我
don't want to get into that trap I don't
不想落入那个陷阱，我不想花
want to be spending a year having
一年的时间开一个又一个的会，
meeting hearing about this possibility
听着这个可能性，然后被
having it changed by this producer I
这个制片人改变。我会事先
game it out and I go no I don't want to
设想一下，不， 不想
do it can you do that when you're
做？你年轻的时候能做吗？
younger kind of 21y old no no takes a
比如21岁？不行不行，这需要
lot of takes a fair amount of experience
很多
in life because when you're 21
人生经验。因为21岁的时候，
everything looks great and exciting man
一切看起来都很棒很刺激，你会想：是
yeah I'll do that why not yeah it'll be
啊，我会做的，为什么不呢？肯定很
fun I'll meet some I'll meet some hot
有趣，我会认识一些
girls I'll do this and the other great
辣妹，我会做这个做那个，
you know etc etc you know you don't you
等等等等。你知道，你
don't have that radar you everything
没有那种洞察力，你觉得一切都很
looks exciting and enticing it
刺激很诱人。这
takes the pain I keep going back to that
需要付出代价。我总是会提到那些
of things that you wasted your time in
你浪费时间的事情，那些
and Things That Failed things that you
失败的事情，那些你
didn't like to teach you the ability to
不喜欢的事情，它们教会你如何
say no and to save your energy for what
说“不”，如何把精力留给你
you really love should a young person
真正热爱的事情。年轻人应该
just be saying yes to
对所有事情都说“是”吗？
everything you know the problem that we
我们
have is everything is has to be this way
面临的问题是，所有事情都必须这样
or that way has to be black or white and
或那样，非黑即白。但事实
it's not like that it's kind of in
并非如此，它介于两者
between you can learn to dance in life
之间。你可以学会在生活中翩翩起舞，
you don't have to go this way or that
你不必非得走这条路或那
way you can kind of do both so the best
条路，你可以两者兼顾。所以
advice I give people is your
我给人们的最好建议是……
20s the best years of your life actually
20多岁是你人生中最美好的时光，其实
I think the 30s are but let's just say
我觉得30多岁才是。但为了方便讨论，我们先假设你
for for argument sake your 20s you're
20多岁，你
young you probably look pretty good
年轻，看起来很棒，身体
you're healthy you know you've got all
健康，一切都顺风顺水。
these things going on for you I want you
我希望你玩得
to have some fun and I want you to have
开心，去
Adventures I don't want you to be 22 and
冒险，我不希望你22岁
go and get a job at Goldman Sachs for
就去高盛找份工作，一辈子都这样。
the rest of your life Etc you need fun
你需要乐趣，需要
you need Adventure you need some
冒险，需要一些
looseness you know you want some
自由，你需要一些
experiences but it has to have some
经历，但这些经历必须要有
direction to it it can't just be I'm
方向。不能只是“我要
going to write poetry I'm going to do
写诗”、“我要玩
rock and roll I'm going to go learn
摇滚”、“我要去学
chemistry I'm going to you know become
化学”、“我要成为这个那个”，
connection at all between all of these
所有这些事情之间没有任何联系。
things just trying everything for the
为了追求新鲜感而尝试一切，
sake of novelty that's a recipe for not
注定不会
being successful because what you want
成功。因为
to happen is you're 30 years old now
你现在30岁了，
you've let your 20s are behind you it's
20多岁已经过去，这
usually a time of Reckoning where you go
通常是一个需要反思和抉择的时期。 妈的，
[__] I'm not so young anymore okay you
我不再年轻了，好吧，你
know I'm getting older all right I've
知道，我正在变老。我已经玩够了，也
had my fun I've had Adventure I'm ready
经历过冒险，现在准备好迎接一些
for something serious and I've learned
严肃的事情了。我
some real skills in life I've for me
在生活中也学到了一些真正的技能。就我
personally I learned how to write um or
个人而言，我学会了写作，或者
whatever it is you didn't just go try 80
其他什么。你不会去尝试80种
different things you you you kind of had
不同的东西，你只会做
four or five that you did you you
四五件你真正
experimented with all right now I know
尝试过的事情。好吧，现在我知道
what I love now I can go down that path
我喜欢什么了，我可以沿着这条路走下去。
and in Mastery I often tell the story to
在“大师”这个栏目里，我经常跟
people of one of the Masters I
人们讲我采访过的一位大师的故事，他叫
interviewed was Paul Graham who was the
保罗·格雷厄姆，是
man who started y combinator you
Y Combinator的创始人。你
probably heard of Y
可能听说过Y
combinator he was somebody who got into
Combinator。
AI when he was like 18 19 years old he
他大概18、19岁的时候就开始接触人工智能了。
was like at MIT I believe right back in
我记得他当时在麻省理工学院，那是
the late 70s when nobody was even
70年代末，那时候根本没人
thinking about it okay he was a hacker
想到人工智能。好吧，他是个黑客，
cuz his father father was was a
因为他父亲是位
scientist who had computers back in the
科学家，在
70s and he learned how to hack early on
70年代就接触过电脑，所以他很早就学会了黑客技术。
okay so he went down the process of
好吧，后来他走上了
going into Academia of of of going into
学术研究的道路，参加了各种
programs of Compu com computer
项目……
programming etc etc and he was on a
他学的是计算机编程等等，就像
track just like huberman at MIT to
麻省理工学院的休伯曼一样，原本打算
become a professor to become proficient
成为一名教授，精通这门学科。
in it and he hated it it was soul
但他讨厌这份工作，觉得它令人窒息。
sucking he didn't like the politics he
他不喜欢政治，
didn't like dealing with the people he
不喜欢与人打交道，
didn't like Academia so he quit
不喜欢学术界，所以他辞职了，
and he became a painter because that's
成为了一名画家，因为
he loved design and he loved visuals he
他热爱设计，热爱视觉艺术。他
comes back to New York he's living in a
回到纽约，住在
loft he's painting he's happy and he's
阁楼里，继续画画，虽然
not making any money and then he hears
没有收入，但他很快乐。后来，他
an advertisement on the radio for I I
在广播里听到一个广告，我
think it was maybe Netscape one of the
记得好像是网景（Netscape）的广告，那是
earliest um you know internet whatever
最早的互联网公司之一，
you call it and they're saying the
他们说
future in in for computers is being able
计算机的未来在于能够
to set buy and sell products on the
在互联网上买卖商品。
internet he ends up creating the first I
他最终创造了第
think one the prototype for all the
一个，我想是
things that we have now Yahoo ended up
我们现在拥有的所有东西的原型。雅虎最终以
buying it for like $5
大约500万美元的价格收购了它，剩下的
million and then the rest is history he
故事大家都知道了。他在
spent his 20s trying something out
20多岁的时候尝试各种事情，
learning real skills he went somewhere
学习真正的技能，后来又去其他地方
else learning something that he loved
学习他热爱的东西。到了
and then he's 30 and he combines the two
30岁，他把这两者结合起来，
together and he's he's a classic example
他是个典型的例子，
because he he gets very bored easily so
因为他很容易感到厌倦。所以，
why combinator is worth billions of
尽管 Combinator 价值数十亿
dollars extremely successful he sells it
美元，极其成功，但他还是把它卖了，然后
gets into something else cuz he likes
去做其他事情，因为他喜欢
writing Etc he's always he's kind of a
写作等等。他总是……某种程度上是
prototype for a lot of what we're
我们
talking about we've spoken a lot about
讨论的很多东西的原型。我们已经谈了很多关于
self-awareness and self and all those
自我意识、自我以及所有
kinds of things what about other people
类似的事情，那么其他人呢？
you know the only thing that seems to
你知道，唯一似乎阻碍我们的是……
stand in the way of all of our goals in
我们人生中许多目标都与
life are other people so if I if I want
他人有关。所以，如果我想
to become exceptional understanding the
变得卓越，了解
human nature of other people and using
他人的人性并将
it in my favor
其为我所用，
where do I start there what are the the
我该从何入手？如何才能精通
using other people's human nature to my
利用他人的人性？
advantage that sounds very narcissistic
这听起来很自恋，也
and very uh awful but
很……糟糕，但事实就是如此。
exactly people as I said the main
正如我所说，
mistake we make in dealing with other
我们在与人交往时犯的主要错误，也是我
people and and it's a common mistake
常犯的错误，就是把
appearances for reality we take their
表象当作真相。我们把他们的
masks for how they appear to us for
面具——他们的
their politeness for their smiles for
礼貌、微笑、“
their saying oh I Loved You etc for the
我爱你”之类的客套话——当作
reality and we have to learn that to
真相。我们必须学会
look behind people's masks we have to
看穿人们的面具，了解他们面具背后
learn what's really really going on
真正发生的事情，
behind them and we have to learn some
我们必须学习一些
Basics about human nature people like to
关于人性的基本知识。人们喜欢
believe that they're essentially good
相信自己本质上是善良的，
you know saintly virtuous however you
圣洁的、有德行的，无论你怎么形容。
want to do it people want to believe
人们喜欢相信自己
that they're intelligent they're you
聪明，你永远不想
never want to feel like I'm not stupid
觉得自己很蠢。
I'm intelligent and the other third
聪明，第三
thing is that they're that they
点是，他们
willpower that they're in control of
意志坚定，能够掌控
their lives they do things because they
自己的生活。他们做事是因为他们自己
decided to do it to tell to make people
决定这么做。告诉别人不要让他们
feel insecure about their intelligence
对自己的智力感到不安，
right to make them feel like they're not
不要让他们觉得自己
moral or they're not good to make them
不道德或不好，不要让他们
feel like they do things not because
觉得自己做事不是出于自愿，而是被迫的，或者
forced to or because they they're not
因为他们缺乏自我
aware of themselves they hate that
认知。​​他们恨你，
they're going to hate you they're going
他们会怨恨你，他们会
to resent you they're going to resist
反抗你。
knowing some Basics about people like
了解这类人的一些基本情况，
that gives you the power to use that for
能让你拥有影响力，可以运用这些知识
influence for persuasion okay
去说服别人。
understanding Envy in the human world
了解人类世界
and on social media Envy is just an it's
和社交媒体中的嫉妒，就像
like a nuclear bomb it's just exploded
一颗核弹，它引爆了
our tendency to feel Envy to compare
我们内心深处的嫉妒，让我们倾向于
ourselves to other people you've got to
与他人比较。你必须
use that for power there's great power
利用这一点来获得力量。嫉妒蕴含着巨大的力量，
in that in a marketing publicity sense
在营销宣传中，
virality
病毒式传播，
what getting other people to be
让人们对其他人
interested in what other people are
正在
doing that's how things sell themselves
做的事情感兴趣，这就是产品自我推销的方式。
if you try and tell people what they
如果你试图告诉人们他们
should buy as opposed to look at what
应该买什么，而不是让他们看看
other people are doing I want to join in
其他人正在做什么，那就行不通了。 参与
on that right knowing about these basic
其中，了解
qualities in human nature about how we
人性中这些基本特质——比如我们如何与他人比较，
like to compare ourselves how we have
我们如何看待自己
etc etc gives you all of this power to
等等——赋予了你
take that human nature and use it for
掌控人性的力量，你可以利用它为
whatever purposes you want for good or
任何你想要的目的做好事，或者
unfortunately some people use it for bad
不幸的是，有些人会用它来作恶。
do we have to lie to be successful and I
我们是否必须撒谎才能成功？我之所以
say this because through reading some of
这么说，是因为在阅读
your work I I heard sentences such as
你的一些作品时，我听到过这样的说法：
you should keep your true intentions
你应该在社交场合隐藏你的真实意图。
in various ways you talk about showing
你经常谈到用各种方式掩饰自己，谈到
up as an actor that sometimes we do need
像演员一样行事，有时我们确实需要
to show up as an actor in our lives so
在生活中扮演这样的角色。
in order to be truly successful I know
为了真正成功，我知道
it's a little bit of a difficult
这个问题有点棘手，
question but do we have to
但我们是否必须
lie look
撒谎？要知道，
being a human being means we
作为一个人，我们天生就会
lie right the moment you open your mouth
撒谎。当你开口
and you speak you are essentially not
说话的那一刻，你实际上并没有
telling the truth you know what doesn't
说真话。你知道什么不会
lie body language non-verbal
说谎吗？肢体语言、非语言
communication the way you smile the look
交流、你的微笑、
in your eyes you can't lie about
你的眼神，这些是无法掩盖的。
that but children three or four years
三四岁的孩子就
old are already learning to craft what
已经开始学习如何巧妙地
they say to mommy or daddy to get what
对爸爸妈妈说话，以达到
they want they're very clever they're
自己的目的，他们非常聪明。 他们
very strategic right they know that if
非常讲究策略，对吧？他们知道
they if they say that they what they
如果直接说出自己
exactly want they won't get it they
想要什么，肯定得不到。所以他们
learn to kind of whine and complain and
学会了抱怨和发牢骚，用
put a certain tone in their voice and to
特定的语气说话。我们都是演员，我们都是
actor a social animal like we are we are
社会动物，人生就是演员。别再为此感到
guilting about about it I'm so sick of
内疚了，我真是受够了。我们都是演员，我们都是黑猩猩的后代。
chimpanzees chimpanzees are concept
黑猩猩是概念
subit actors read the literature on that
潜意识演员，去读读相关的文献吧。
they know how to deceive incredibly well
它们非常擅长欺骗，
and they don't even have language to
而且它们甚至没有语言可以用来
deceive right so we are actors the
欺骗，对吧？所以我们都是演员。当
moment you go out in the public you're
你出现在公共场合时，你
not telling people oh you're fat you're
不会对别人说“哦，你很胖”、“你很丑”、“你写得真烂”、“
don't like what you're wearing you never
你穿的衣服真难看”，你永远不会那样
do that you're an actor when you see
做。你是个演员。当你见到
your father you act a certain way when
父亲时，你会表现得像个演员；当
you see a little kid you act a certain
你见到小孩时，你会表现得像个演员；当
way when you see little kitty cat you
你见到小猫咪时，你会用特定的语气说话；
have a certain tone in your voice when
当
you deal with your boss the person who
你和老板——也就是给你
pays for the for your podcast I don't
播客付费的人——打交道时，你会用特定的语气说话。我不
know if there is such a person you wear
知道…… 确实存在这样一种人：你扮演
you act a different way you're
不同的角色，你的言行举止也各不相同，你
constantly changing how who you are and
不断地改变着自己，改变着你的为人。前
how you are Act One Moment you're Robert
一秒你还是罗伯特·
dairo the next moment you're I don't
戴罗，下一秒你就变成了我不
know what other actor you are but you're
知道是哪个演员，但你确实在
you're changing your roles depending on
根据
who you're dealing with I'm so tired of
你面对的人而变换角色。我厌倦了
people not recognizing this fact that we
人们不承认这一点：我们
are all actors that we are constantly
都是演员，我们不断地
deceiving yes there are differences
欺骗。是的，谎言有区别，
there are qualities of lying you know I
谎言也有不同的性质。我
understand that there's Donald Trump
知道有像唐纳德·特朗普那样的
lying and there's the lying of the
谎言，也有
everyday white lies in which we have to
日常生活中为了成功而不得不说的善意谎言等等。谎言也有
there are degrees I understand that and
程度之分，我明白这一点，
some lying could be very harmful and and
有些谎言最终会造成极大的危害，
very counterproductive in the end but
适得其反。但是，当
the moment you enter the world and the
你来到这个世界，当
moment you open your mouth you are in
你开口说话的那一刻，在
some ways already an actor and you are
某种程度上，你已经是一名演员，你已经在
already using forms of deception why
使用各种形式的欺骗。为什么
can't we be our true
我们不能做真实的
selves because it would irritate people
自己呢？因为那样会惹恼别人，
because it would gr you
因为那样会让人反感。
know I don't know about you but I
我不知道你怎么想，但我很
appreciate
欣赏
politeness right I go somewhere and I
礼貌，对吧？我去某个地方，如果我
know someone's being polite I know that
知道有人很礼貌，我就会觉得很舒服。 我知道
they're not necessarily meaning it but
他们未必是真心这么想，但这样确实不错，对
constantly hitting each other it'd be so
吧？感觉很顺畅，让一切都变得顺畅起来。如果人们不礼貌，就像两块金属不停地互相碰撞，我会很
annoying you'd want to kill yourself or
烦躁，甚至想自杀或者
you want to kill people You' become a k
杀人。你会变成一个
a murderer you know social life depends
杀人犯。你知道，社交生活依赖
on that kind of smoothness those
于这种顺畅的
interactions so we need that to some
互动，所以我们在某种程度上需要它。
degree if we were just always telling
如果我们总是告诉
people what we really
别人我们真实的
thought our our world would collapse
想法，我们的世界明天就会崩溃。那么，
tomorrow what about showing our weakness
展现我们的弱点呢？
I've got this quote from you that says
我听过你说过一句话：如果你
if you are weak and ask for little
软弱，只求一点点，
little is what you will get but if you
你得到的也只会很少；但如果你
act strong making firm even outrageous
表现得强硬，提出坚定甚至过分的
demands you will create the opposite
要求，你就会给人留下截然相反的
impression people will think that you
印象。人们会认为你
confident and that it must be based on
自信，而且你的自信一定有其依据。
something real you will earn their
你会赢得他们的
respect which in turn will translate to
尊重，而这反过来又会转化为
real
真正的
leverage well it's it's about certain
影响力。当然，这只是针对特定
situations so I don't want you to apply
情况而言，所以我不希望你把
that idea to everything in life and some
这个理念应用到生活的方方面面。有些
people make the mistake when they read
人读了《
the 48 Laws of Power they think well I'm
权力的48条法则》后会犯一个错误，那就是认为“我
going to use that everywhere no it
要把这些法则应用到所有地方”。 不，这
applies to certain situations so let's
适用于某些特定情况。
say you're
比如说，你在
negotiating and I know I dealt with this
谈判，我知道我自己也经历过这种情况。
myself I'm actually a fairly timid
我天生其实比较胆小，
person by nature but I've learned to
但我学会了如何
cultivate the opposite so if you're
克服这一点。如果你在为
for your time for your services and
你的时间或服务定价，而
you're not very confident and you kind
你又不太自信，只要价很低，那
that's what you're going to get because
你最终得到的也只会是这个价，因为
people aren't going to they're assuming
人们不会接受，他们会认为
that you're that you're not really up to
你能力不足。
the task you say all right $20,000 is
你会说，好吧，2万美元
enough that's what they'll give you but
就够了，他们就会给你这个价。但
if you raise your price high and you say
如果你把价格提高，用
it with the right voice and you believe
合适的语气说出来，并且相信自己，
in it they're going to go wow that
他们就会觉得，哇，这个
person is is confident and if they turn
人真自信。如果他们拒绝了
you down that's fine because somebody
你，也没关系，因为总会有人
else will give you that price if you you
愿意出这个价。你要根据自己对
about yourself if you think that you're
自己的认知来设定自己的价值。如果你觉得自己
worthless if you're not very good at it
一文不值，或者觉得自己能力不行，
other people pick that up as you were
别人会察觉到这一点。你刚才
talking I was thinking about um Adam
说的，我想到了……
Newman from Wei work and this
来自魏的亚当·纽曼。
conversation I heard with him and the
我工作时听到过他和
founder of soft Bank in the back of a
软银创始人
taxi where Adam Newman's asking for a
亚当·纽曼在出租车后座的对话。
billion and then the owner of soft Bank
当时纽曼向软银老板要了十亿美元，
this very eccentric Chinese very rich
这位非常古怪的中国
Asian man goes do you know what Adam the
富豪说：“亚当，你知道吗？你
only problem with you is that you're not
唯一的问题就是不够有
ambitious enough and he writes him a
野心。”然后，在和纽曼相处了大概十二分钟后，他就给纽曼开了一张
check I believe for like five or 10 bli
支票，我记得是五千万到一千万。
being with him and I always thought
我一直在想这件事，心想：
about that and thought Jesus what if I
天哪，如果我
just started asking life for way more if
开始向生活索取更多，如果
I just multiplied all of these emails
我把所有
that I send and requests I make by 10
发送的邮件和提出的请求都乘以十，
course of 10 years well yeah um probably
十年后我的生活会发生什么变化？嗯，或许
you probably would have gotten a lot
你会得到比
more than you got without asking for
不索取时多得多的东西。
because we we we we're creatures that as
因为我们就像
I said before we look at the appearances
我之前说的，总是会关注
of things look it's it's very very easy
事物的表象。举个很简单的
metaphor
例子，
here you go into a social situation like
你去参加一个社交活动，比如
a party and you go up to somebody who's
聚会，你走到一个看起来有点
kind of nervous and insecure and anxious
紧张、不自信、焦虑的人面前……
and I'm not criticizing that because we
我不是在批评这种做法，因为我们都有不
all have insecurities I have many of
安全感，我自己也有很多。
them myself but you go up to somebody
但如果你走到
like that and it makes you feel kind of
那样的人面前，你会感到
nervous and
紧张和
insecure right and you're kind of
不安，对吧？你会
fumbling for words and it kind of goes
结结巴巴地找词，气氛会变得有点
bit of awkwardness happens reverse that
尴尬。反过来，如果
you go up to somebody else and they're
你走到另一个人面前，他们很
kind of confident they look you in the
自信，他们会直视你的
eye you know their voice is strong their
眼睛，他们的声音很有力量，
body language is strong they connect to
肢体语言也很有力，他们能与
you whoa you think it brings out that
你建立联系，哇，你会觉得这激发了你内心深处的那种自信。
part of you who's like that you might be
你可能会感到
intimidated but it also might bring out
畏惧，但也可能激发出
your own kind of confident self I
你自身的自信。我
remember being around 50 Cent who's a
记得和50 Cent在一起的时候，他
very charismatic confident to the point
非常有魅力，自信到近乎
ridiculousness and it was very
夸张，而且这种自信很有
infectious I felt that way after being
感染力。和
around him for a couple hours I was with
他相处几个小时后，我就感觉到了这一点。我和
him for several months it rubbed off on
他相处了几个月，这种影响潜移默化地影响了
me right we have these kind of viral
我。我们之间确实存在这种病毒式的
contagious Effects by people so if you
传染效应。所以，如果你
project strength and
展现出力量和
confidence you know and I understand
自信，你知道，我知道
it's a little different for women which
这对女性来说有点不同，这
is an interesting subject because
是一个很有意思的话题，因为
sometimes projecting that for a woman
有时女性展现出这种力量和自信
will rub the wrong way because people
会适得其反，因为人们
will think that and it's a terrible qual
会认为…… 我们女性身上一个很糟糕的特质就是，人们
judged by a different standard where
用不同的标准来评判她们，好像她们
that'll seem like they're a [__] or
就是个泼妇似的。
something like that so I understand that
所以我明白
there are nuances here and that the game
这里面有很多细微差别，
is different for women as it is for
女性面临的挑战也和
people of other ethnicities as well you
其他种族的人不同。所以这
know so it's not just one way or the
不是非此即彼的问题。即使是
degree that even for the woman that you
女性，如果你散发出一种
have this air of conf confidence that
自信的气质，
you believe in what you're doing that
相信自己所做的事情，
you believe you're worth it IT projects
相信自己值得拥有这一切，这种自信自然会传递
itself to other people you don't have to
给别人。你不需要
scream and shout you don't have to
大喊大叫，也不需要
demand 10 billion dollar but if you feel
索要100亿美元，但如果你感到
confident if you feel you're worth this
自信，如果你觉得自己值这么
amount of money it will project outward
多钱，这种自信就会通过
to other people body language yeah want
肢体语言传递给别人。
to talk about that does it you know you
是的，你想谈谈这个吗？你知道，你
said earlier it's one of the things we
之前说过，这是我们无法否认的事情之一。
you still look for in today when you're
在今天，当你
trying to read someone their body
试图解读一个人的肢体
language are there certain cues is there
语言时，你还会关注什么？有哪些特定的线索？
postures or well you know you you got to
比如姿势？你知道，
in Reading non-verbal communication it's
解读非语言交流是
a different form of intelligence it's
一种不同的智慧形式。 它
not algorithms it's not formulaic it's
不是算法，也不是公式，它是
human it's emotional it's empathetic
人性的，是情感的，是同理心的，
it's a reading without words it's ATT
是一种无言的解读，是与
tuning yourself to other people so I
他人建立联系的技巧。我会
attune myself to people's emotions to
调整自己去感受他人的情绪，感受
the vibe that they give off in an over
他们整体散发出的氛围。
overall sense a Galt is one thing that I
我喜欢用一种叫做“高尔特”（Galt）的方法来解读他们。
like to do so if I had to give it a word
如果非要用一个词来形容，
I would say anxious or I would have to
我会说焦虑，或者
say outgoing and extroverted or I would
外向，或者
have to say impatient or whatever
急躁等等。
there's an energy that kind of defines
有一种能量定义了
them it's a word and that word is not
他们，这个词并不
precise but there is an overall feel
精确，但它确实能给我一种整体的感觉。
that I get from a person and then I'm
当然，我也会
always looking at
关注一些
specifics it's not like I'm sitting
细节，但我并不是有意识地坐在
there
那里，
consciously in my head going through a
在脑子里过一遍
checklist I'm just feeling certain
清单，我只是在感受某些
things and I'm feeling that the eyes are
东西。比如，我感觉他们的眼神空洞，
kind of dead they're not engaging with
没有和
me and you can't put that into words but
我交流。这种感觉很难用语言表达，但
you know the feeling so when someone's
你知道的。当有人
looking at you but they're not really
看着你，但眼神却空洞无物时，
looking at you you know what that feels
你知道那种感觉，对吧？
like don't you mhm and a lot of
嗯，很多
Psychopathic people a lot of narcissists
精神病患者，很多自恋者都
do that
会这样做。
so part of their face pretends to be
他们脸上的一部分表情假装
interested in you they are looking at
对你感兴趣，他们看着
you in the eye but they're not really
你的眼睛，但其实并没有真正
looking at you they're thinking of
看着你，他们心里想着别的
something else they're seeing in you
事情，想着能从你身上得到
what they can get out of you they're
什么，他们把
seeing you as an object right eyes are
你当成一个物品。对吧？眼神
hard to lie they tell you something now
很难说谎，它们会告诉你一些事情。
actors very skilled actors can kind of
演员，尤其是技艺高超的演员，可以
create some of these Impressions but one
营造出一些印象，但
thing that they can't fake is the tone
他们无法伪装的一点是
in their voice and actors will tell you
语气。演员会告诉你，
that it's the hardest thing to actually
这是最难有
consciously control so the voice of a
意识地控制的东西。一个人的声音能
person tells you a lot about their
告诉你很多关于他们的
confidence levels tells you a lot
自信程度、他们的
General emotional tone about their
整体情绪基调、他们的
character about who they are it's very
性格以及他们是什么样的人的信息。声音
difficult to fake and when it's hesitant
很难伪装，当声音犹豫、
when it's like stammering when it's not
结巴，或者不结巴的时候，
you know you can kind of sense something
你都能
from people's voice and it's very hard
从人们的声音中感受到一些东西，这很难
to fake and then the smile the
伪装。还有笑容，
things if you know how to read it
如果你懂得如何解读，笑容能告诉你很多不同的东西。
there's the authentic smile which I'm
有一种发自内心的笑容，我
not going to fake right now but well I
现在不想假装，但它
just it lights up the whole face you
真的能让整张脸都亮起来，你
know like you really feel Joy you can't
知道吗？就像你真的感到快乐一样，
you don't can't foret your eyes go up
你无法忘记，你的眼睛会抬起来，
your cheeks go up everything kind of
脸颊也会鼓起来，一切都浑然一体，对吧？
connects together right the fake
假
Smiles you know yeah
笑，你知道，
we've all seen the fake just when the
我们都见过那种假笑，
mouth goes up and the rest of the face
嘴角上扬，但脸上的其他表情却
doesn't bother Stephen I really like you
毫无反应。比如，斯蒂芬，我真的很喜欢你，
you're really you're
你真的
wonderful you
很棒，你
know most of the time most Smiles are
知道，大多数时候，大多数笑容都是
fake but you can kind of when you see
假的，但当你看到发自
the genuine smile and you go that's what
内心的笑容，并且意识到是什么让你露出了
caused the genuine smile you should
真挚的笑容时，你应该有所察觉。
become aware of that and then body
肢体
language tells you a lot like is
语言也能告诉你很多信息，比如，当有人在
you're standing up at a at a party is
聚会上站着和你说话时，他们的
there body kind of facing another
身体是否朝向另一个
Direction while they're talking to you
方向，
or they're kind of looking out there way
或者他们是否在和
while they're talking to you that means
你说话时目光游离，这意味着
they're not really interested in you
他们对你并不感兴趣，
they're not really engaged in you right
他们并没有真正投入到你身上，对吧？还有，
also when you catch people by surprise
当你突然出现，人们来不及
fake smile I often tell people to do
伪装笑容时，你也能感受到他们的笑容。 我经常告诉别人这样做：假设
this like there's somebody in your
你办公室里有个家伙，
office and you don't know whether
你不知道
they're a snake or they're actually
他是阴险狡诈还是
genuinely your friend you suspect could
真心朋友，你怀疑这两种情况都有可能。于是，
go either way you kind of approach them
你
from an angle right and you surprise
从侧面接近他，给他一个惊喜。
them you come up to them you go they
你走上前去，他
look at you and for a second you detect
看着你，一瞬间，你捕捉到
what we call a micro expression of of
我们称之为“轻蔑的微表情”，
disdain and then they put on the smile
然后他立刻露出笑容。
that micro expression which scientists
科学家和心理学家研究过的这种微表情
psychologists have studied lasts for
持续时间不到一秒，真的不到
like less than a second much less than a
一秒。
second you have to be able to read it
你必须学会​​解读它，
but it reveals whether they actually
但它能揭示他们是否真的
like you or they're totally false they
喜欢你，还是完全虚情假意。他们装
can't fake it so if you come to straight
不出来。所以，如果你直接走过去，他们会说：“
on they'll oh hi Stephen I love great to
哦，嗨，斯蒂芬，我爱你，很高兴
see you they come oh they they kind of
见到你。”他们会假装热情，
pretend then they try and act and you
然后努力表现，你
you can get Clues like that there's so
就能从中获得线索。
many ways to read body language it's
解读肢体语言的方法有很多，这是
such a fascinating subject I could go on
一个非常迷人的话题，我可以滔滔不绝地讲上几个
for hours about it how important is it
小时。它有多重要？
you know you're talking about colleagues
你知道，你刚才说的是同事
and team members there and earlier you
和团队成员，而且你之前
said that people are contagious how
说过，人们的行为会传染，
important do you think it is to the
你认为它有多重要？ 这关系到
success of our lives and I paused there
我们人生的成功，我在这里停顿了一下，
because success means it's a personal
因为成功意味着它既是个人
thing it's a professional thing to
层面的，也是职业层面的，我们需要
surround ourselves with the right group
与合适的
of people and to be intentional about
人为伍，并且要有意识地这样做，
that it's very important
这非常重要。
um I have a chapter in excuse me in the
嗯，不好意思，我在《权力的48条法则》里有一章专门讲“
infection and um I think it's an
感染”，我想
experience many of us have had where
我们很多人都有过这样的经历：
you're around
你身边的
somebody who seems at first glance to be
人乍一看
very interesting
很有趣，
and they they they become your friend
他们成了你的朋友，
maybe they're very dramatic and they
也许他们很戏剧化，
have all these stories to tell and they
有很多故事要讲，他们
seem almost slightly larger than life
看起来几乎有点超乎寻常，
and you engage with them and then you
你和他们交往，然后你们
become friends and then slowly slowly
成了朋友，然后慢慢地，慢慢地，
slowly it becomes clear that that
慢慢地，你会发现
they're a little bit nuts right they're
他们有点疯，对吧？他们
always talking about how this person
总是说这个人怎么
screwed them how that person screwed
坑了他们，那个人怎么坑了
them how this boyfriend or girlfriend
他们，这个男朋友或女朋友有多糟糕多
was so awful and so nasty you to re you
恶心。你
begin to realize is this true or is it
开始意识到，这些是真的吗？或者
maybe there that the pro they the
也许
problem but now they're your friend and
问题出在他们身上，但现在他们是你的朋友，
now you're emotionally attached to them
你对他们产生了情感上的依恋，
and now they have room to play all these
现在他们有空间对你玩弄各种手段，
kind of games on you and all of their
他们所有的
drama starts infecting you and it's like
戏剧性行为开始感染你。 你就会想，
God damn it I want to get away from this
天哪，我真想逃离这个
person but I can't they've infected you
人，但我做不到。他们的负能量感染了你，让你无法摆脱。
under your skin and so uh you have to
所以，你必须
avoid people like that
远离这样的人。在
with them that they are a drama queen or
和他们交往之前，你必须先了解他们是不是个“戏精”或“
a drama King because there just as many
戏王”，因为很多
men out there who have this quality you
男人都有这种特质。你
have to see that they are that they play
必须看清他们，他们总是扮演
the victim of all of everybody else but
受害者，但
actually they kind of bring it onto
实际上，这一切都是他们咎由自取。
themselves some people are genuinely
有些人确实很
unfortunate bad things have happened to
不幸，遭遇了不幸，
them and it's not their fault I'm never
但这并非他们的错。我并不是
saying it's a misconception about that
说
chapter that you should avoid everybody
你应该远离所有
who's unfortunate there are people and a
不幸的人。确实，
lot of people out there whose
很多人的
circumstances have put made them who you
境遇造就了他们现在的样子，你
know in their what's going on it's not
知道，他们正在经历什么，这并非
their fault right but there are other
他们的错。但还有一些
people you have to recognize that the
人，你必须认识到，
bad things that happened to them are
他们遭遇的不幸是他们咎由自取，
things that they have brought on because
因为
they have this infecting power it comes
他们有一种传染力，这种传染力源于他们内心
from Deep insecurity you don't want them
深处的不安全感。你不想让这样的人出现
in your life being around insecure
在你的生活中，和不安全的
people will make you insecure being
人在一起只会让你变得不安全。 和那些自信、目标明确、做事有条理、努力
together who are trying to make things
创造
and accomplish things because there's so
和实现目标的人在一起，会感觉好很多。因为现在
many people out there who talk and talk
太多人只会夸夸其谈，
and talk but never do anything being
却从不行动。和那些真正做事、有所作为、成功创业、把这
who've made this that or the other their
或那作为人生
goal to be around because they'll infect
目标的人在一起，会感觉好很多，因为
you with their positive energy
他们的正能量会感染你。“亦敌亦友”？
yeah do we all have Frenemies and how do
我们都有“亦敌亦友”吗？我们该如何识别“亦敌亦
Frenemies well hopefully we all don't
友”呢？希望我们都
have them but um in the laws of human
没有，但根据人性规律，在
nature and in in several of my books I
我的几本书中，我都
talk about the phenomenon of Envy which
谈到了嫉妒这种现象。嫉妒是一种
is very very powerful human trait it has
非常强大的人类特质，它的
roots very ancient Roots we know that in
根源非常古老。我们知道，在
societies from thousands of years ago
几千年前的狩猎采集社会中，
Envy was a real problem and so they
嫉妒是一个真正的问题。因此，他们
create all kinds of rituals to avoid
创造了各种各样的仪式来避免
Envy where the moment somebody in a
嫉妒。比如，
tribe received a gift they had to give
部落里有人收到礼物后，必须把它分给
it to other members so they wouldn't
其他成员，以免遭到
face Envy because facing Envy you could
嫉妒。因为一旦遭到嫉妒，你可能会被
be murdered for it so you learned all of
杀害。所以，人们学会了所有
these rituals and we've noticed that
这些仪式。我们注意到……
chimpanzees feel Envy you give some one
黑猩猩也会嫉妒。比如，你给一只地位
of the higher up chimps because they're
较高的黑猩猩
very hierarchical a grape and all all
一颗葡萄，因为它们的等级制度非常森严，
the other chimps are very wanting that
其他黑猩猩也都想要这颗
grape as well and they feel envy and etc
葡萄，它们就会嫉妒，等等
etc so it's an extremely human
等等。所以，嫉妒是一种极其人性化的
emotion the thing that we don't realize
情感。然而，我们往往没有意识到，
though that the people most likely to
最容易产生
feel Envy first of all we all feel Envy
嫉妒的人其实是……首先，我们都会嫉妒，
we're all comparing ourselves to other
我们都在拿自己和别人比较。我现在就经常感到嫉妒，比如
I envy Ryan holiday because he's you
我嫉妒瑞恩·霍利迪，因为他比我
know so 30 years younger he's sold so
年轻30岁，他的书卖得那么好，他
many books you know he's got all this
拥有那么多
great stuff I I know I know what Envy is
成就。我知道嫉妒是什么感觉，
like I feel it we all feel small degrees
我感同身受。我们都会感受到一定程度的
of Envy but there are people I call it
嫉妒，但有些人会表现出我所说的“
passive Envy but active Envy means
被动嫉妒”。而主动嫉妒则意味着
people act on it they do something to
人们会采取行动，他们会做一些
hurt you they sabotage you and some way
伤害你、破坏你的事情。“亦敌亦友”
Frenemies are the classic scenario so
就是一个典型的例子，
somebody who feels envious of you ends
一个嫉妒你的人最终会和
up befriending you and consciously they
你成为朋友，他们
may not be even aware of that they think
可能意识不到这一点，他们可能心想“
well I would do want to like them but
嗯，我也想喜欢他们”，但
unconsciously they feel Envy they think
潜意识里，他们仍然感到嫉妒。 他们认为
that you have success that you don't
你获得了你
necessarily deserve that you have what
未必配得上的成功，你拥有了
they want right they become your friend
他们想要的东西，对吧？他们就变成了 你以为他们是你的朋友，他们会用各种
and they they charm you Etc Etc and then
花言巧语讨好你等等，然后，你突然发现
lo and behold you start noticing all
他们开始做出各种
you weren't expecting cuz you're
你意想不到的丑陋行为。因为你是
there're your friend they start saying
他们的朋友，他们开始说一些
[__] comments that get under your skin
刻薄的话，让
that make you feel insecure they take
你感到不舒服，让你没有安全感。他们会拿走
things from you they act in ways that
你的东西，他们的行为
are hurtful but because they're your
会伤害你。但因为他们是你的
friend your first instinct is to blame
朋友，你的第一反应是责怪
yourself well maybe it's my fault that
自己。也许他们这样做是我的错，
they've done this maybe I'm actually to
也许我真的应该
blame for what for what they're saying
为他们说的话负责
etc etc ET so I believe behind the
等等。所以我认为，在
frines phenomenon is this this phenomena
友谊现象背后，隐藏着一种
of Envy where the person secretly wants
嫉妒的现象，这个人暗地里想要
what you have and they're becoming your
你拥有的东西，他们接近你是为了
friends so that they can wound you and
伤害你。
what's best to do is to recognize that
最好的办法是认清这一点。一个
somebody who's befriending you out of
出于
Envy is they're in a rush to be your
嫉妒而接近你的朋友的一个常见特征是，他们急于和你
friend normally we like to take it a
做朋友。通常我们喜欢慢慢来，
little bit slow we just don't let
不会轻易让
anybody into our lives we like to vet
任何人进入我们的生活，我们喜欢
them a little bit beforehand right we
事先对他们进行一些考察，对吧？
don't trust everybody but the person who
不要相信所有人，但那些
feels Envy is like I love you you're
心怀嫉妒的人却会说：“我爱你，你
fantastic I want to be your friend we
太棒了，我想和你做朋友，我们得出
got to hang out let's go out for dinner
去玩，
the next night they're in a hurry that's
第二天晚上一起吃晚饭吧。”他们很着急，这
a sign that something else is going on
表明事情另有隐情，
because that's not natural what about
因为这不自然。
when friends become
如果朋友变成了亦敌亦
Frenemies because sometimes through the
友呢？因为有时，随着我们自身的
process of US changing yes you might
变化，你可能会
Inspire that Envy
引发嫉妒。是的，
yes like your status changes we've all
比如你的地位发生了变化，我们都经历过这种情况，
had to deal with that I've had to deal
我也经历过。
with that as well you have
你获得了
success and you you came from a
成功，而你出身
background where with where you weren't
并不
so successful and your friends are still
成功，你的朋友还在你
there and they Envy you and they're not
身边，他们嫉妒你，对
very nice to you and uh you know it's
你不太友好。你知道，
it's not a good quality and I've I've
这不是一种好品质。我理解这种
I've I've understand the quality I
品质，我
understand where it comes from and I've
理解它的根源，我在《
I wrote about it in human nature where
人性》一书中也写过它，
we're all aware of the of this of the
我们都意识到了这种
what we call sha Freud Shan Freud means
我们称之为“嫉妒”的现象。弗洛伊德认为，嫉妒是指从他人
you take pleasure in other people's pain
的痛苦中获得快乐。
so you hear a friend didn't get the job
所以，当你听到一个朋友没能得到…… 他们
that they wanted to get and you go oh
得到了自己想要的工作，你会想，哦，
I'm sorry but deep down inside you're
对不起，但内心深处你其实挺
kind of kind of happy you know and we
高兴的，你知道吗？我们都会
all go through that right the opposite
经历这种感觉，对吧？相反的
is mitfa it's an expression that n a
是“mitfa”，这是一个
coin which means you feel Joy for other
硬币上的表达，意思是为他人感到高兴。
people I like to try and cultivate some
我喜欢培养一些
of the higher qualities in life so if
生活中更高的品质，所以如果
somebody i' my first thing is I might
有人取得了成功，我的第一反应可能是
feel a twinge of Envy but then I go it's
一丝嫉妒，但随后我会想，这对
great for them I'm actually very happy
他们来说太棒了，我真的很高兴，
I'm excited I share their joy in what
我很兴奋，我分享了他们所
has happened right but it's not natural
经历的喜悦，对吧？但这并不自然。
so when somebody that you know and
所以，当你认识
you've known for a long time has success
很久的人获得了成功时，
in life your first thing is to be they
你的第一反应是他们
didn't deserve it they kind of cheap
不配，你觉得他们是通过卑鄙的手段获得的。
their way to it okay as we talked about
就像我们一
in the very beginning you confront that
开始讨论的那样，你要自己面对这种
ugly emotion yourself and you go that's
丑陋的情绪，告诉自己，这
not who I want to be and you go I'm
不是我想成为的人，你要让自己产生
going to make myself feel the opposite
相反的感觉，我要让
I'm going to make myself feel happy for
自己为
their
他们的
success it's not natural and most people
成功感到高兴。这并不自然，大多数人
don't go through that and I know
不会经历这种感觉，就我
personally from people I knew before I
个人而言，我从我认识的人那里就了解这一点。
life they're the ones that give me the
那些在生活中取得过任何成就的人，
fewest amount of compliments for my
对我的书的赞美最少。
books they never read my books in the
他们一开始就没读过我的书，他们
their with what they say they've got a
说话很吝啬，
pinched look on their face whereas
脸上带着一丝不屑。而
people I've never met before in my life
那些我素未谋面的人却对
give me all kinds of compliments why is
我赞不绝口。这是为什么呢？
that because they're envious they're
因为他们嫉妒我，他们感到不快，
upset are you are you threatening them
你是在威胁他们吗？
because they see themselves like you
因为他们觉得自己和你很像，
because they knew you and you're where
因为他们认识你，而你来自他们曾经
you're from where they were from so
来自的地方，所以
you're even more threatening you're
你对他们来说更具威胁性，你就像一面
holding up a mirror to them in a way
镜子，
that makes them feel even more
让他们感到更加
uncomfortable well they're not going to
不自在。但他们不会
feel that way so what people will go
这么想的。人们会经历这样的过程，
through in that sense is and this is how
这就是我的
I I I I I think through oh Robert sold
想法：哦，罗伯特出卖了
himself out he wrote a book that's evil
自己，他写了一本邪恶、
that's nasty that manipulative I didn't
恶心、充满操控的书，我以前不知道
think he was like that I thought he was
他是这样的人，我一直以为他是个
this nice person oh I don't like this
好人。哦，我不喜欢这
book is ugly they'll go through that
本书，它太糟糕了。他们会经历这个
process they'll stay my friend because
过程，但他们仍然是我的朋友，因为
we've had years and years together it's
我们认识很多年了。 多年来，这种情况非常
very very common at least I know that
普遍，至少我知道
they go they do that with my books even
他们会这样对待我的书。
though my later book books aren't like
即使我后来的书不像《
the 48 Laws of Power they still have it
权力的48条法则》那样，但字里行间仍然保留着那种感觉：
in the grain that this guy who used to
一个曾经那么和蔼可亲的人，却写出了
be so sweet and nice with these nasty
如此恶毒、充满
evil manipulative mellan books he sold
操控欲的书，彻底背叛了自己。那么，《
Laws of Power that some people are
权力的48条法则》的核心究竟是什么，才会让一些人感到如此反感呢？究竟是什么
single most triggering concept or the
概念最能引发他们的反感，或者说
most um controversial or the concept
最具争议性，又或者说，是什么概念让
that people just had a surface level
人们
onsite without even really reading it
甚至还没真正阅读就产生了表面的过敏反应？他们
they just no no yeah they read the back
只是看了
of the book they read the names of the
看书的封底，看到了法则的名称，然后就说：“
laws and they go oh that's that's ugly
哦，这太丑陋了。”
and a lot of times they've had to deal
很多时候，他们
with ugly people in their lives and so
在生活中都遇到过丑陋的人，所以
that's when I see I see the authentic
当我看到他们真实的
disgust reaction I understand it that
厌恶反应时，我理解他们的感受。
they had to deal with someone who's very
他们不得不面对一个极具
manipulative and they find it disgusting
操控性的人，所以他们觉得这本书令人作呕。
of course when I get to have a rational
当然，当我和
discussion with them and I calmed down
他们进行理性讨论，平复了
their emotional reaction I said look if
他们的情绪后，我会说…… 听着，如果
you had the 48 Laws of Power before this
你在被这个人操纵之前就读过《权力的48条法则》，
person manipulated you they would have
他们就永远
never been able to manipulate you that
无法操纵你。这
book is the best defense you could ever
本书是你
have in your life it's like a shield
人生中最好的防御，就像一面盾牌。
once you've read it you know all the
一旦你读过它，你就会知道
tricks people are playing on you right
人们都在对你耍哪些花招，对吧？
they know they're posing as a friend and
他们知道自己伪装成朋友，像
acting like a spy right they're
间谍一样行事，对吧？他们
concealing their intentions you know etc
隐藏着自己的真实意图，等等
etc etc it's showing you all of these
等等。这本书会向你揭露所有这些
tricks okay but that's when they calm
伎俩。好吧，但前提是他们冷静
down an able to say that
下来，能够说出这些话。
but the idea that we're not
但我们并非
angels that we don't all have the the
天使，我们并非都怀着
best intentions in life that I'm writing
美好的愿望，而我却在写
a manual that they think for how to
一本关于如何
manipulate how to deceive how to con
操纵、如何欺骗、如何诈骗他人的手册，这会让很多人感到
people triggers people very
非常不适。
much A lot of people who've who've
很多经历过
suffered in life who've had a lot of
人生苦难、饱受
pain understand that there's irony in
痛苦的人都明白
The Book book they don't read it the
这本书的讽刺之处。他们不会像其他人那样
same way they read it knowing yeah I've
去读它，而是会说：“是的，我也经历过这些，
had this happens this is what people are
这就是人们的为人，
like I'm okay with it I'm cool with it
我接受，我不在乎。”
and I must say I don't know if this will
我必须说…… 我不知道这么说会不会
come off wrong but a lot of the readers
不妥，但早期
who responded most positively to the 48
对《权力的48条法则》反响最积极的读者中，很多都是
African-Americans people like 50 people
非裔美国人，比如
in the hip-hop business Etc they didn't
嘻哈圈的50 Cent等等。他们对人性没有
have any
丝毫
Illusions about human nature about how
幻想，不相信
good we are because they've seen the
我们有多善良，因为他们一生都在见识人性的阴暗面。50 Cent
said when he got into the record
说过，他刚入行的时候，
business he was shocked at how political
震惊于
people were how manipulative they were
人们的政治手腕和操控手段。
so they weren't having that same
所以他们并没有像其他人那样产生同样的
reaction they weren't having the guilty
反应，他们没有那种内疚感，
reaction like oh that I don't want to
比如“哦，我不想
read about that why do we why do we even
看这个，我们为什么要
have to discuss that that's not that's
讨论这个？这不好，这没用，这
not positive that's not helpful that's I
无益”。我
think a lot of what triggered people
觉得这才是真正触动人心的地方。说来也巧，
it's funny cuz I was speaking to a CIA
我最近和一位CIA
agent recently and he said something at
特工
the end of our conversation to me he
聊天，他最后跟我
said you know one of the things I've
说，他在
come to learn from being in the CIA is
CIA工作期间学到的一件事就是，他
that I no longer believe that equality
不再相信平等
is possible and he he said equality
是可能的。他说“平等，
equality yeah because that's just not
平等，是啊”，因为这根本不可能。
the way that the human world works and
人类世界的运作方式，
we all pretend we want equality we all
我们都假装想要平等，我们都
pretend we want everyone to be equal but
假装希望人人平等，但
if you look at every game we play
如果你看看我们参与的每一场游戏，
whether we're politicians or we're
无论是政客、商人
business people or whatever it's all
还是其他任何角色，都离不开
about hierarchies and power and getting
等级制度、权力以及
ahead even that the sheer nature of
向上攀升。甚至连
being a politician is campaigning to get
政客的本质就是竞选，为了获得
into a position of you know objective
客观
power and I want wanted to know what you
权力而努力。我想知道你对此有何看法。
thought about that well I mean there's
我的意思是，这其中确实存在
some truth to it in the sense of there's
一些真理，因为
something in our nature that is
我们的本性中确实存在某种
hierarchical that has deep roots in us
根深蒂固的等级观念。
but I do believe in one form of
但我相信有一种形式的
equality um and that is everybody at
平等，那就是每个人从
their birth has the possibility for
出生起就拥有
following the path that I talk about in
追随我所说的“精通之路”的可能，这条路通往
Mastery for being great for fulfilling
卓越，通往实现
their Destiny for being the unique
命运，通往成为独一无二的
individual that they are at Birth so
个体。
everybody is born with a a DNA that will
每个人都拥有独一无二的DNA，无论
never be replicated in the past or in
过去还是将来，都无法复制。
about every person and and there's a
每个人都是独一无二的，
uniqueness about your parents about your
你的父母、你的
background about your early years right
背景、你的早年经历也都是独一无二的。
and that uniqueness is a seed that if
这种独特性就像一颗种子，
you PL if you cultivate it and you and
如果你…… 培养它，你，
you use it and you know your purpose and
你运用它，你知道你的目标，
you you mine it for power
你从中汲取力量。在
in in in Mastery I interviewed one of
精通之道中，我采访过一位
the master I interviewed was a woman
大师，
named Tempo
名叫坦波·
grandon who was born with severe
格兰顿（Tempo Grandon）。她出生时患有严重的
autism at the age of two she was about
自闭症，两岁时差点被
to be committed to a hospital for the
送进医院度过
rest of her life she was she was like
余生。她当时几乎处于一种
almost like in a walking
行走的
coma for some reason they got her a
昏迷状态。不知何故，他们给她安排了
teacher to teacher language and she
教师对教师的语言治疗，她
started emerging a little bit and then
开始慢慢恢复意识，然后逐渐
slowly she blossomed
绽放。她
and she realized be it was something
意识到，
common to a lot of autistic people that
很多自闭症患者都有一个共同点：
she had an incredible connection to
她与动物有着不可思议的联系。
animals and a lot of autistic people
很多自闭症患者都有这种特质，但
have that she couldn't connect to people
她无法与人建立联系，因为人
they were so tricky and deceptive she
太狡猾、太虚伪，
she didn't know how to deal with them
她不知道该如何与他们相处。
but animals give her a horse a dog a cow
但动物，比如马、狗、牛，让
she felt like she was one of them she
她感觉自己就像它们中的一员。
ended up following that path and
最终，她选择了这条路，
becoming a highlevel animal behavioral
成为了一位高级动物行为
scientist who um she was born with
科学家。她出生时患有
autism about to be committed to a
自闭症，差点被送进
hospital and it she achieved incredible
医院，但她
success in life as a
作为一名
scientist I do honestly and I'm not
科学家取得了令人瞩目的成就。我真心相信，我没有
faking I do honestly believe that
夸张，我真的相信。 我相信
everyone has that
每个人都有这种
potential but it it's not equal in the
潜力，但结果却不尽相同。
outcomes of that there are a lot of PE
很多
the majority people don't follow that
人追求卓越，但大多数人并没有走上这
path but I do believe everybody has that
条路。但我确实相信每个人都有这种
potential is that potential like
潜力。这种潜力是指
objective greatness or is it our own
客观意义上的伟大，还是我们
subjective greatness I I can become the
主观的伟大？我能成为
greatest version of Steven or do you
最伟大的史蒂夫吗？或者你
believe that everyone could become great
认为每个人都能变得伟大，就像成为像
in the world like you know Steve Jobs or
史蒂夫·乔布斯那样的世界上最优秀的人吗？不，
no they're not you don't have to be the
他们不是。你不必成为
very best in in the world I mean I uh
世界上最优秀的人。我的意思是，
when I Mastery came out we were uh the
当我的《大师》出版时，《
New York Times wanted to do a story
纽约时报》想
about my house in the home section okay
在家居版块报道我的房子。好吧，为什么？好吧，
well why but all right right I never get
我从来没有从
any publicity from mainstream media so
主流媒体那里获得过任何宣传。
okay fine so I had to quickly upgrade my
好吧，没关系。所以我不得不迅速翻新我的
house because they were going to come
房子，因为他们要带着
over with photo photographers and we got
摄影师过来。我们找了
a man over to do the tile work on my
个人来铺我那看起来糟透了的露台瓷砖。
hell and I I told people this guy was a
我告诉人们，这个人是个
true Master he wasn't like making six
真正的大师，他不是那种年收入六位数的人，没
figures nobody would ever write an
人会为
article about him he will die and no one
他写文章，他会去世，而且没人
will ever know that but I could see in
会知道。但我能从他身上看到那种
the quiet quality and how well he
沉静的品质。 他对瓷砖的
understood it and the care that he took
理解有多透彻，他投入了多少心血，
in it and how much he enjoyed you know
以及他多么享受
creating a beautiful effect with tile
用瓷砖创造出美妙的效果——
work that he was a master it doesn't
他是一位大师。你
have to be the best ever you don't have
不必成为史上最佳，你不必
to be famous and successful there are
成名成名，成功也并非易事。成功有
grades of this there are degrees of it
等级之分，程度也各不相同。
some
有些
people is just being a great parent they
人只是优秀的父母，他们善于
are very social they're very empathetic
社交，富有同理心，
and they're not maybe going to
他们或许不会
become extreme successful Finance person
成为金融界的巨擘，
but they're really good at raising their
但他们非常擅长养育
children and they put to put a lot of
子女，并为此付出了大量的
effort and Care into it that's fantastic
努力和关爱，这很棒。
you don't have to be famous you don't
你不必成名，不必
have to be Steve Jobs there are levels
成为史蒂夫·乔布斯，成功有层次之分。
of it right but the sense of this was
但这种感觉正是
what I was meant to accomplish and I'm
我命中注定要完成的，我正在
I'm following it and I'm happy what I do
追寻它，我为我
I feel fulfilled by my work and I can go
的工作感到快乐，我从工作中获得了满足感，我可以继续做下去。我
on doing it I take it seriously I care
认真对待它，我关心
about it
它。
I do believe that that anybody can have
我相信每个人都能
that level of power in their life I
在生活中拥有这种力量。说实话，我
think I struggle with that if I'm being
认为我在这方面还在努力。是的，就我
honest yeah on a personal level I
个人而言，我一直在
struggle with um enough being
努力做到“够了”，
enough and also I think I've grown up in
并且我认为我…… 我成长于这样一个
the generation where there's so much
时代：
comparison everywhere we look when we
到处都是比较，
open up our phones and Instagram that
打开手机和Instagram，
you kind of always are led to believe
你就会觉得总觉得
that you're not quite there yet now I've
自己还不够好。现在我开始思考，也许这反而是件
that's a good thing because it drives
好事，因为它能激励
you forward it's that pressure you
你前进。就像你刚才
described it's that creates that urgency
说的，那种压力会让人产生紧迫感和
that desperation so maybe I should never
渴望。所以也许我永远不应该
believe I'm there yet but then also I
觉得自己已经成功了。但同时，我
wonder am I going to defer happiness off
又在想，我是不是要把幸福推迟
into the future because I think it's
到未来，因为我觉得幸福似乎隐藏在
behind some kind of accomplishment or
某种成就、
job title or you know success in my life
职位或人生成功背后？
and you know when I hear about that
你知道，当我听到
Tyler I go that person that was tying
泰勒在铺
your um patio I'm really jealous because
露台瓷砖的时候，我真的会很嫉妒，因为
they sound contempt with much less than
他看起来比我更自恋，而我却能做到这些。那么，
what is the correct correct answer is it
正确的答案是什么呢？是像
to be the happy Tyler who's tiling the
泰勒那样快乐地铺着
patio or is it to be the um
露台瓷砖，还是像
impatient Steve Jobs that's striving for
乔布斯那样急于研发
the personal
个人
computer well it depends on who you are
电脑？这取决于你是谁，
we're all individuals we all have our
我们都是独立的个体，都有自己
our unique energies it's the fact that
独特的能量。 关键在于
you engage you love that you're
你投入其中，热爱它，并与它建立
emotionally connected to it that it
情感联系，这能给
gives you a sense of fulfillment that
你带来满足感，让
you're not looking over your shoulder oh
你不会总是想着“哦，
I I could be doing this
我本可以做这个”，这样
instead I'm fine with that I doesn't
挺好。我
have to be the Steve Jobs who's
不需要成为像史蒂夫·乔布斯那样
continually dissatisfied who's fouy and
永远不满足、永远疯狂、
who always has to have more I'm not
永远想要更多的人。我也不
against that either I don't know why we
反对那样，我不明白为什么我们
have to be so judgmental if people are
要如此评判别人。如果人们在
following the path and they are in love
追寻自己的道路，热爱自己所做的事情，
with what they do and they have a
并且与它有着
genuine connection to it I'm not going
真挚的联系，我不会
to judge it because they're not famous
因为他们不出名，
or because they're not trying to be the
或者因为他们没有努力成为
greatest the Michael Jordan of tying or
最伟大的迈克尔·乔丹等等就去评判他们。
whatever Etc I think it's fine and you
我认为这很好。如果你
you're not happy you want to you want to
不满足，你想做到极致，
crush it you want to be have the number
你想拥有排名
one podcast that's fine as well why
第一的播客，那也很好。为什么
diversity in our world the most
我们的世界不能有这种多样性呢？
important thing for both those types of
对于这两种人来说，最重要的是——那些
people the the people that have that
拥有
sort of insatiable sense of ambition but
永不满足的野心的人，
also the people that are contempt with
以及那些…… 就
from what I had there is they both love
我所见，他们俩都热爱
what they're doing uh and they both have
自己正在做的事情，而且他们都具备
those core components that you described
你之前描述的那些核心要素，
earlier like they both feel the
比如他们都
challenge in their work still and that
仍然能感受到工作中的挑战。这种
challenge might be okay I'm going to do
挑战可能是“我
a bigger patio today or it might be I'm
今天要建一个更大的露台”，也可能是“我
business tomorrow for someone else and
明天要为别人启动一个价值十亿美元的项目”。关键在于
it's really about those cool components
这些重要的要素，
of like challenge meaning purpose yeah
比如挑战、意义和目标。
yeah because what you don't want is you
因为你肯定不想到了
don't want to be in your 50s in your 60s
五六十岁，
she's facing death you know cuz your
面临死亡的时候才后悔，你知道，因为你的
days are numbered who knows how long
生命有限，谁知道
you're going to live and you're going to
你还能活多久，然后你会想：该死，
go damn it I could have done something
我本可以成就一番事业的。
with my life when I was a child I had
我小时候有很多
these dreams I thought I was going to be
梦想，我以为自己会在这方面很
really great at it and I never realized
出色，但我从未实现过。我
it I went off on these other paths I was
走上了其他的道路，
lost I thought I was happy but but I
迷失了方向。我以为自己很幸福，但我
never really fulfilled any of those
从未真正实现过任何
childhood dreams or those fantasies you
童年的梦想或幻想。你
know it's a terrible terrible feeling
知道，这是一种非常糟糕的感觉，
and I want people to avoid that as long
我希望人们能够避免这种感觉。
as it's something that engages you
它让你全身心投入，与
that's connected to that child that you
你内心深处的那个孩子相连，
were it's something that you love and
它是你所热爱的，
that you you can create these challenges
也是你可以
for
为
you is death a motivator for
自己创造挑战的。死亡是
you well um it certainly is
你的动力吗？嗯，
now you know because um my days are are
现在当然是了。因为我的生命真的在
literally numbered you reach a certain
倒计时。到了某个
age and you know you can literally count
年纪，你真的可以数清自己还剩下多少
the numbers of the days that might be
天。
left you and I nearly died several years
几年前我差点因为中风而丧命，离死亡只有一步之遥。当时
dying you know I was driving my car and
我正在开车，
if my wife hadn't
如果不是我妻子
suddenly seen something I wouldn't be
突然发现了什么，我
talking to you here right now either I
现在就不会在这里和你说话了。要么我会出车祸身亡，
would have crashed and died or I would
要么我会
have had such bad brain damage that I'd
脑损伤严重到变成
be a vegetable so I know about death I
植物人。所以我了解死亡，我每天
feel it in my body every day I wake up I
醒来都能感受到它的存在。我每天早上醒来都会进行
do my morning meditation I'm a whereare
冥想。在我的冥想练习中，我会设想
where this could be my last thought I
这可能是我最后的念头：我可能
could die 10 seconds from now what do I
10秒钟后就会死去。
want in my head in those last seconds do
在最后的几秒钟里，我希望我的脑海里有什么？是
I want to have some petty little thought
一些琐碎的念头，
about somebody who did this or said that
比如某人做了什么或说了什么，
or do I want to have something else
还是我希望有一些更
greater in my head I'm constantly aware
伟大的想法？ 我一直都意识到
of my mortality and with the book that
自己的生命有限，而
I'm writing it's always it's always in
我正在写的这本书也让我时刻想着这件事。
frankly I'm aware that I might die
坦白说，我知道我可能在
before I finish the book so now I've
完成这本书之前就死了。现在我已经
written 2third of it if I die tomorrow
写了三分之二，如果我明天就死了，
the book can be published and it's okay
这本书仍然可以出版，这也没关系，
I can live with that but uh you know I'm
我可以接受。但是，你知道，我
in a hurry to get it done because I know
急于完成它，因为我知道死亡随时
it could happen at any moment you know
可能发生，
and it almost happened to me so I'm
而且它差点就发生在我身上。所以我
continually aware of it but not in a bad
一直都意识到这一点，但这并不是一种消极的
sense in a way of it kind of makes gives
感觉。从某种程度上说，它赋予了
meaning to my life it makes me
我的生命意义，让我
aware of how you know valuable each
意识到每
moment is and how things that everybody
一刻的珍贵，以及每个人……当
I look out my window I see people doing
我望向窗外，看到人们做着
things that I can't do anymore and I go
我再也做不了的事情时，我会想，
they take it all for granted they walk
他们把这一切都视为理所当然，他们浑然
around unaware of their mortality of how
不觉自己的生命有限，浑然不觉
their body could break down at any day
自己的身体随时都可能崩溃。
now I'm aware of it so I'm not going to
现在我意识到了这一点，所以我不会
feel Envy because I my mind is at a
感到嫉妒，因为我的思想已经提升到了一个
different level I'm aware of the of the
不同的层次，我意识到
ephemeral nature of life and it makes
生命的短暂，这让
everything kind of beautiful to me makes
一切都变得有意义。 对我来说，这很美，让
me appreciate everything around I don't
我更加珍惜周围的一切。我不想说得太严肃，
mean to be too sacr about this because
因为这可能会让人觉得很严肃，
it could come off that way because there
毕竟它也有
is a dark side to it and I definitely in
阴暗的一面。在
my dreams and in my thoughts I have a
我的梦里和脑海里，我确实经常感受到
lot of that Darkness but I believe the
这种阴暗。但我相信，对
awareness of death is is a beautiful
死亡的认知是一件非常
beautiful thing it's it's it's it's it
美好的事情。它让
makes everything intense and makes
一切都变得强烈，让一切都因
glow with that awareness if you were my
这种认知而闪耀光芒。如果你和我
age I've just turned
同龄，我刚满
31 wow you're a
31岁，哇，你还是个
kid Jesus Christ
孩子呢！我的天哪，
man I hate
我真羡慕
you I was 31 I was The Biggest Loser
你。我31岁的时候可是《超级减肥王》的冠军！
that's amazing if I could
这太不可思议了。如果我能把
to my head that you've got from the life
你从人生经历中获得的那种认知移植到我的脑海里，包括你
you've lived but also from that stroke
中风后对
mortality that it gave you and the
死亡的感悟，以及它让你意识到
ephemerality of life that it showed you
生命的短暂，
how do you think I would live my life
你觉得我会如何以不同的方式生活？
your life differently when you were 31
你31岁的时候又会如何以不同的方式生活？你
uh you know I I make a point of I never
知道，我从来不做
go through that exercise because I
这种假设，因为我
believe in something called aor Fati
相信一种叫做“命运”（aor fati）的东西，
which means love of your fate everything
意思是热爱你的命运，一切的
happened for a purpose I wouldn't have
发生都是为了……
done anything differently if I I had to
如果让我
go back because it all led to the right
回到过去，我不会改变我当初的选择，因为一切都朝着正确的方向发展。
things so if I'd been in a hurry when I
如果我
was 22 to be successful as a writer I
22岁时急于成为成功的作家，我就
would have never been able to write the
永远无法写出
books that I wrote would have all gone a
我写的那些书，它们都会偏离
skew who knows where I would have ended
正轨，谁知道我会走到哪一步。我对现在的生活
up I'm very very happy with I don't
非常满意，我没有
anything but if you're young what often
任何遗憾。但如果你年轻，经常会
happens
发生这样的情况：
is because your life the pattern of your
你的
life if you think of it as a weaving is
人生轨迹，如果你把它想象成一幅织布画，可能只完成了
only like for you is only like a third
三分之一，
woven right for me it's like 2third
对我来说，大概完成了三分之二。
woven so I can see all of these patterns
所以我能看到
that you can't see in your life but at
你生活中看不到的所有模式。但在
your stage you know you tend to think
你这个年纪，你往往会觉得
I've got all of this time ahead of me
时间还很长，
I'm so young i' I can do this I can I
我还年轻，我可以做这个，我可以
can go travel here I can do this
去旅行，我可以做这个
business and that business ET Etc you
生意，做那个生意等等。你
don't feel that sense of urgency you
感受不到那种紧迫感，你
don't realize that tomorrow you could be
没有意识到明天你可能被
hit by a car tomorrow you could suddenly
车撞，明天你可能突然
be diagnosed with cancer people are
被诊断出癌症，人们正在
dying now in their 30s and 40s I read
死去。 现在到了三四十岁，我发现
unfortunately when you get older a bad
很不幸，年纪大了之后有个坏
habit is you start reading the obituary
习惯，就是开始看讣告。
pages I don't know why um and you start
我不知道为什么，然后就开始
reading about people a lot of people who
读到很多
are in their 40s and 50s are dying left
四五十岁的人去世的消息。
right and center today for various
如今，各种各样的
reasons it can happen and what it does
原因接踵而至，这是无法避免的。而这件事会让人意识到，
says I only have so much time I wanted
我的时间有限，我一直想
to accomplish this one thing that I've
完成一件想做的事，却总是
been putting off okay okay you wrote
拖延。好吧，也许你写完了
your book maybe there's something else
书，也许还有其他
that you've always wanted to do but you
一直想做却
have never done and you're kind of
从未做过的事，你一直在拖延。这种
putting it off a sense of urgency a
紧迫感，这种意识到
sense that your time is relatively short
自己时间相对较少的感觉，其实是
is a good thing the other thing is it
件好事。另一方面，
makes as I said it makes everything a
正如我所说，它会让一切都变得更加
little more intense a little more a glow
强烈，更加令人振奋。
is the word I like to use
我喜欢用“现在”这个词。
so I used to swim like three days a week
我以前每周游泳三天，
and I would swim long distances and I
而且游很长的距离，我非常
loved it it was my greatest therapy I
喜欢游泳，它是我最好的疗愈方式。我
just loved getting out of my head and
喜欢抛开一切烦恼，沉浸在
just going being in the water okay but I
水里。但
never appreciated it until now when I
直到现在，当我
can't do it so I want you to appreciate
无法再游泳时，我才真正体会到它的价值。所以我希望你们珍惜
you going to the gym having your health
去健身房锻炼、拥有健康、
to being able to do these things don't
能够做这些事情的机会，不要把它们视为
look at it like take it for granted and
理所当然。
it pisses me off that young people take
年轻人把
all the stuff for granted they think
所有东西都视为理所当然，这让我很生气。他们觉得
that I'm privileged because I have this
我因为取得了这些成就就享有特权
success C when you're young you have all
。当你年轻的时候，你拥有所有
those privileges you have your health
这些特权，你的健康，以及
you have other things that are could be
其他可能
taken away from you don't take for
失去的东西。不要把
granted these things in your life that
生活中这些
you have that are not going to last
不会
forever think in those terms and think
永远存在的东西视为理所当然。要从这个角度去思考，想想
you becomes when you have that mindset
当你拥有这种心态时，你周围的一切都会变得更加重要。
one of the things I think I worry that I
我觉得我最担心自己会习以为常的一件事就是我和
my romantic relationship with my partner
伴侣的感情。
and you know hearing your story of being
听了你
in that car that day
那天在车里的经历，我更加
it's literally evident that your
确信，你的
romantic partner can save your
伴侣可以救你的
life she did and um yeah uh you know
命，她做到了。 是啊，你知道，
we've been together for a while I'm not
我们在一起很久了，我不会
going to say how many years because she
说多少年，因为她
doesn't like hearing that because um so
不喜欢听这个，因为，
you know we have a a a deep rich past
你知道，我们有着一段深厚而丰富的过去，这是
and it and it's a wonderful thing and
一件美好的事情，
she saved my life and saving someone's
她救了我的命，救人一
life man it really is important it
命真的很重要，
really means a lot of ch of changes
意义非凡，它能改变很多
things and in my book that I'm writing
事情。在我正在写的书中，
now I wrote a chapter on love which is
我专门写了一章关于爱的章节，这显然是
something I've never written about
我以前从未写过的——
but I've never written about love and I
我写过关于诱惑之类的，但我从未
wrote
写过关于爱的章节。我写的是那种
about the in the incredible the sublime
不可思议的、崇高的
quality that you can have when you allow
品质，当你允许
yourself to go deeper and deeper and
自己越来越深入地沉浸于
deeper into that falling process where
那种坠落的过程中，你会体验到这种品质，
of your defenses you get rid of all the
你会放下你的自我，放下你的防御，放下所有的阻力，让自己坠落， ...
vulnerable they don't want any pain and
他们不想变得脆弱，不想承受任何痛苦，
falling for another person and letting
爱上另一个人，
go of your defenses opens you up to pain
放下防备，就意味着要承受痛苦，对吧？
right and we just want to we don't want
我们只想……我们不想体验这些，
to experience that we want to be
我们想要刀枪不入，
invulnerable and it's like cutting off
这就像切断了
all the richest experiences in life and
生命中最美好的体验。
so I wrote that chapter addressing that
所以我写了那一章来探讨这个问题，我
and say let go of your defenses let go
说，放下你的防备，放下
of your resistance let yourself go into
你的抗拒，让自己进入
that process of falling let feel what it
坠入爱河的过程，去感受
feels like to have your ego dissolved in
在
the presence of another person and care
另一个人面前放下自我，
more about them than you care about
更在乎对方而不是自己的感觉。
you mentioned a second
你刚才提到了
ago dark thoughts and dark
黑暗的想法和
dreams we all have dark thoughts our
噩梦，我们都有黑暗的想法，这些想法只属于
dark thoughts are our
我们
own how do you go about dealing with
自己。你是如何处理这些
dark thoughts and what are those dark
黑暗想法的？
thoughts that you're able to
你又有哪些黑暗想法可以
share
分享呢？嗯，
well you know um in my dreams I'll be
你知道，在我的梦里，我会
doing all kinds of weird things uh a lot
做各种各样奇怪的事情，很多
of times there'll be guilt like like did
时候都会有内疚感，比如，
I actually murder that person are the
我真的杀了那个人吗？
police actually after me damn it what's
警察真的在追捕我吗？该死，接下来会发生什么？
to my reputation then I wake up you know
我的名誉会怎么样？然后我就醒了。你知道，
so all that kind of stuff happens but
诸如此类的事情都会发生，而且…… 我对
also doubts about myself and depression
自己的怀疑、抑郁，
and about I've I've dealt my whole life
以及关于我自己的一切。我一生都在与这种
with feelings of like not being very
感觉作斗争，觉得自己不够
worthy like even doubting My
好，甚至怀疑自己的
Success doubting that my work work is
成功，怀疑自己的工作是否有效，
any good doubting that I deserve it I
怀疑自己是否配得上这一切。
had you know a lot of periods in my life
你知道，我人生中有很多段时期
where I I wasn't
都不
successful and
成功，而且
um I kind of had it ingrained in me that
我根深蒂固地认为
I could do better I could do better I
我可以做得更好，我可以做得更好，我可以做得更好。我
could do better I wasn't a good parent
没有好好对待
to myself I was very tough on myself and
自己，我对自己非常苛刻，
a lot of my dark thoughts are I'm still
我的很多阴暗想法都源于此。我现在仍然
very tough on myself and it's
对自己非常苛刻。
like you know the other dark thoughts
你知道，我还有一些阴暗的想法，比如
is I can't do the things that I used to
我做不了以前能做的事情，
when you can't like hike when you can't
当你不能徒步旅行、不能
swim when you can't go out on your
游泳、不能骑
bicycle when you can't travel
自行车、不能像
normally do do I is it really worth it
往常一样旅​​行时，生活还有意义吗？这一切真的值得吗？
you know maybe maybe death wouldn't be
也许，也许死亡
so bad compared to that I go through
比这更可怕。我经历过
that and then I go yeah I talk myself
这些，然后我又一次又一次地说服自己放弃。
out of it again and again and again but
但
my dark thoughts are about about myself
我的阴暗想法都与我自身、
and my doubts and about the state of my
我的怀疑以及……有关。 就我
body as it is right now kind of thing if
目前的身体状况而言，如果
I said to you that I had those same
我告诉你，我对你的身体状况也有同样的
doubts about you know if I was if we
怀疑，比如我们是否
were identical in every way and I said
在各方面都完全相同，我说：“
Robert I'm having a lot of doubts about
罗伯特，我有很多怀疑，我
I can't go out my bicycle I can't do the
不能骑自行车，我不能做
things I used to do I'm wondering if
以前能做的事情，我在想
life is worth living and I asked you for
生命是否值得活下去。”我向你寻求
advice said I don't know what to do
建议，我说我不知道​​该如何克服
about the self-doubt I have about these
我对这些书的自我怀疑，
you say to me well um I would say um
你会对我说什么呢？嗯，我会说，生活中
there's a lot of people we talk a lot in
我们经常听到很多人
life who [__] their way who say
吹嘘
they've accomplished this and the other
自己取得了这样那样的成就，
and they've never done anything you have
但他们实际上什么都没做。你出版了
a book out there that you can be very
一本书，你可以为此感到非常
proud of that you could die tomorrow and
自豪，即使你明天就死了，它也会成为
it's like a momento that we live on
我们
forever and you've accomplished that
永远铭记的纪念品。你已经做到了这一点，
you've accomplished this stuff with your
你通过你的
podcast you've actually made things so
播客取得了这些成就，你真正地创造了一些东西，所以专注于此，专注于这样一个
focus on that focus on the fact that so
事实：
many people never get out of bed and and
很多人终其一生碌碌无为，
amount to anything so you've built
一事无成，而你却创造了一些
things you've accomplished things focus
东西。 专注于已取得的成就，
on that and then about your
然后再想想你的
body well you know when you're dead it's
身体。你知道，当你死去的时候，一切都
it's all gone who knows what lot what
消失了，谁知道死后会是什么样。
there is on the other side but just
但
think of of the insanity of what it
想想活着的意义是多么不可思议。这
chapter in my in my new book the odds
在我的新书《
against you Stephen of ever being born
斯蒂芬，你出生的几率简直低得不可思议》中还有另一章。
are absolutely insane and I describe
我
those odds in the book and I go through
在书中描述了这些几率，
from the very first cells that ever from
从最初的细胞，从
Life forming a planet Earth to the
生命形成地球，到最终
evolution leading to us sitting here is
进化到我们坐在这里，这简直
unbelievable so that you are alive is an
难以置信。所以，你活着本身就是一件
incredible astounding thing and you have
不可思议的奇迹，你必须好好
to think about that and you have to
想想。你必须
think about
想想，
just seeing the sky just being aware is
仅仅是看到天空，仅仅是意识到这一点，
is an amazing thing so I often think
就是一件多么神奇的事情。我经常会想到那些有
about people who are suicidal there are
自杀倾向的人，
a lot of people like that in life
生活中有很多这样的人，
particularly nowadays and I know because
尤其是在现在。我知道，因为
I went through that
我在30岁出头
period most strongly in my early to
到30岁中期经历过一段非常艰难的时期，当时
mid-30s as I was contemplating the lack
我一直在思考
of success in my life um you know and
自己生活中缺乏成功。你知道，
what kept me going was I still believe
支撑我走下去的是，我仍然相信
that I could accomplish something so
自己可以成就一些事情。所以
even in my darkest moments I managed to
即使在我最黑暗的时刻，我也设法让
pull myself out but then I I think of
自己振作起来。 但我转念一想，有些
people who maybe don't have that energy
人可能没有那种精力，正一步步走向
hole and I know from my own experience
深渊。根据我自身的经验，我知道，即使
that hearing somebody tell them that
有人告诉他们
life is is incredibly amazing fact won't
生命是多么美好，
have any effect on them right because
对他们来说也毫无作用，因为
it's it doesn't connect to them
这无法触动他们的
emotionally and I often think how could
情感。我常常思考，
I connect to them emotionally how could
我该如何与他们建立情感联系？
I make it clear to them that there's
我该如何让他们明白，生命中有些东西
something there that that's worth
值得
preserving I don't have the answer here
珍惜？今天我没有答案，
today but I think about that all the
但我一直在思考这个问题，比如，
time like how would I deal with somebody
我该如何面对一个有
who is suicid and I get people writing
自杀倾向的人？我经常收到这样的来信，
me like that and we've had I've had
我的
relatives in those situations before so
亲戚也曾经历过类似的情况。所以，
that's something I think a lot
我一直在思考这个问题。这是一个
about it's it's a difficult question to
很难
answer what you have to say to that
回答的问题：在这种情况下，你该对那个人说什么，才能让
person in that situation to get them to
他们
believe in the sublime to get them to
相信生命的美好，才能让他们
believe that there's life is worth
相信生命值得
living I Ponder
珍惜？我在想，
whether what maybe you need to do is to
或许你需要做的，是引导他们迈出
get them to take the first step to
第一步，让他们
create evidence for themselves somehow
自己去创造证据。
whatever that small first step is I
无论这小小的一步是什么，
think that's great I think that's I
我认为这都很棒。 我
think that's spot on that's exactly what
觉得你说得太对了，这正是
you have to do they they have to come to
你需要做的。他们必须自己意识到这一点，
to the realization themselves and
并
through some action that you get them to
通过你引导他们
do which makes them gives them a little
采取的行动，让他们对自己产生一丝
bit of an ounce of believe in themsel
信心，
then the spiral can turn around so I
这样才能扭转局面。所以我
think you're right it has to be come
觉得你说得对，这必须源于他们自身，必须
from them and it has to come through
通过
something that they actually do all the
他们实际去做的事情来实现。光说不练是没用的。至于具体该怎么做，
know I would like to think about and
我一直在思考，
it's and it depends on the individual
这取决于个人，
but that I think that is the way to do
但我认为这才是正确的方法。
it you're writing this book at the
你目前正在写一本
moment called the sublime right are you
叫做《崇高》的书，对吗？你
writing that book
写这本书是
because of the situation you found
因为你在经历创伤
yourself in after having the Str and and
后，经历了一段关于“生命意义
going through that journey of saying why
何在”的探索之旅，并最终找到了
of the sublime that we all
我们每个人都与生俱来的崇高感吗？说实话，
you about 20 years ago I had the idea
大约20年前我就有了写这
for the book I read a book on the
本书的想法。我读过一本关于这个
subject and I got excited about it
主题的书，我被它深深吸引，
because they were explaining it as it's
因为书中把它描述为
a kind of experience that's very hard to
一种非常独特的体验。 难以
verbalize that goes outside of what we
言表，那种感觉超越了我们
normally experience and I got very
通常的体验。我当时
excited by the idea and I planned to
对这个想法非常兴奋，并计划
write that book and then around after
写那本书。
war that was going to be my fourth book
战争结束后，那将是我的第四本书，
and my agent was getting all prepared to
我的经纪人也做好了一切准备去
sell it and then I got hooked on 50 Cent
卖它。然后我迷上了50 Cent，于是就先写了
and I did that book instead and I put it
那本书，把那本书搁置了。
on the back burner and then Mastery came
之后《精通》这本书出现了，
up and I got hooked under that and
我又被它吸引，
suddenly it kind of got pushed aside and
突然间，那本书就被搁置了。
then in in human nature first of all the
然后，在《人性》这
last chapter in the 50 Cent book is on
本书里，首先，50 Cent那本书的
what 50 and facing it then the last
最后一
chapter in human nature is about the
章是关于
sublime it's about death and
崇高的，是关于死亡，以及50 Cent如何面对
mortality and the irony is that two and
死亡。讽刺的是，在
a half months after finishing that
完成那一章的两个半月后，
chapter in the book I I nearly died but
我差点死了。但
what I had planned originally was I was
我最初的计划是
going to go to the goby desert and and
去戈壁沙漠，
and walk across the goby desert I was
徒步穿越戈壁沙漠，
going to go swim with w Wales you know
去威尔士游泳——你知道，就是
literally Wales in New Zealand I was
新西兰的威尔士，去火地岛，体验
going to have all of these Sublime
所有这些崇高的
experiences and write about
感受。 写下
them and now I can't do any of that
这些，现在我什么都做不了了，我
right all I can do is sit in my my
只能坐在
little room in my house at my desk and
家里的小房间里，坐在书桌前
write the book it's all in my
写书。一切都在我的
head the book is so much better because
脑海里。正因为如此，这本书才变得更好。
of that so it's changed I can't go to
它改变了。我不能去
the GOI desert I can't swim with well or
戈伊沙漠，我不能游泳，否则
I drown I can't go to Tiara Del fuo I
我会淹死。我不能去蒂亚拉德尔福。我
can only sit in my office look at the
只能坐在办公室里，看看
birds go through the books that I'm
鸟儿，翻翻我正在
reading and write the book keeping in
读的书，然后一边写一边
mind other people and what's going on in
想着其他人，想着
the world in their life and my
世界上正在发生的事情，想着他们的生活，也想着我自己的
limitations so ironically the book has
局限。所以讽刺的是，这本书反而
become better because I had to go
变得更好了，因为我不得不
through this experience but nearly dying
经历这一切。差点丧命的经历就像是
my head all right it's time to write
脑海里响起了警钟：好了，是时候写
that book you're not putting it off any
这本书了，你不能再拖延了。它是否
longer and has it forced you to find the
迫使你
sublime in the
在
everyday life well obviously I mean um
日常生活中发现崇高之美？显然，我的意思是，
I'm writing right now a
我现在正在写一
chapter on what I call the
章，关于我称之为“德
deont which is an ancient Greek concept
翁特”（deont）的东西。这是一个古希腊的概念，
that all of us are born with like a
我们每个人生来就拥有它，就像一个
guardian
守护神。
Spirit right I know it sounds very
我知道这听起来很…… 这听起来很
mystical but a lot of psychologists
神秘，但很多
contemporary psychologists have written
当代心理学家都写过
about the dayon phenomena theide that
关于“第二自我”现象的文章，认为
you have a second self a kind of higher
你拥有第二个自我，一种更高的
self that in some way is guiding you and
自我，它在某种程度上指引着你。
it has a lot to do with some of the
这与
things we've talked about purpose
我们之前讨论的一些内容，比如人生目标
Etc and I have to think about it I have
等等，密切相关。我必须思考这个问题，我必须从
to think about it in terms of my own
我自身的生活角度来思考它。
life I have to think about is there
我必须思考，我内心深处是否还有
something else inside of me that's
其他东西在
communicating to me what does that mean
与我交流？这意味着什么？
how does that connect with other ideas
它如何与关于宇宙的其他理念联系起来？
about the Universe I get to read books
我读过很多
about it it's a very very exciting
相关的书籍，这是一个非常非常令人兴奋的
process it's it's keeping me alive right
过程，它让我保持活力。
now and then you know I write a chapter
你知道，我写了一章
about animals and what's Sublime about
关于动物以及
interspecies communication and now I get
跨物种交流的崇高之处，现在我
to look at my cat I don't look at my cat
看我的猫的方式和以前不一样了。我不再像写那一章之前那样看待我的猫，也
or I don't look at the birds the same
不再像以前那样看待鸟儿了。
so it's changing me and it's Lifting me
所以，它正在改变我，它让我摆脱了那种
strokes we all have to go through
中风患者的状态。我们所有人都要经历
terrible diseases all of us
可怕的疾病，
unfortunately unless we die by an
不幸的是，除非我们死于
accident cancer Etc Strokes
意外、癌症等等。 中风后最常
the number one thing that happens is is
遇到的情况就是
terrible depression to suddenly lose
极度抑郁，突然失去
your body and what you could do and so
身体和能力，感觉一切都失去了意义。所以，这本书让
this has kept me out of that depression
我远离了抑郁。
say you said that all of your books have
你说过你的所有作品都
been kind of focused on different
侧重于不同的
subjects and that's very much the case
主题，确实如此。
the different books but they're all very
不同作品之间有时只有三行文字的关联，但它们都
much focused on a variety of different
聚焦于各种不同的主题。
subjects if there
如果有
was a
一个
message that kind of brings all of your
信息能将你所有的
work together if this was your last day
作品联系起来，如果这是你在地球上的最后一天，
Earth what would the message that you
你
would want to leave the world with
想留给世人的信息是什么？
be wow that's
哇，这
a really good question
真是个好问题。
um a lot of my
嗯，我的很多
books have to do with um the reality of
书都与
our life and and what not not what we
我们生活的现实有关，而不是我们
want to believe not our our our fake
想要相信的，不是我们对生活的虚假
ideas about it not our Illusions Etc but
想法，也不是我们的幻觉等等，而是
what life is really really like this is
生活的真实面貌。这就是
the human animal this is how they behave
人类，这就是他们的行为方式，
this is what will seduce them this will
什么会诱惑他们，
was what will turn them off this is how
什么会让他们反感，这就是
strategies will get us what we want in
我们如何运用策略获得想要的东西，
life this is how you can master your
这就是你如何掌握你的
subject not the [__] thing that
领域，而不是
people tell you about master where you
人们告诉你的那种靠
can take a drug where you can hack your
药物就能掌握的胡扯。 你可以通过一些技巧
way to Mastery this is the truth this is
达到精通，这就是真相，这就是
the reality so all of books the through
现实。我所有书的
line is this is what the world is really
主线都是：这就是世界的真实面貌。
like it's not ugly it's not beautiful it
它既不丑陋，也不美丽，它就是它本身。能够接受
the world as it is to see things as they
世界的本来面目，如实地看待事物，这很棒。这在某种程度上是一种
are it kind of is liberating and in a
解脱，某种程度上来说，与
connect to the reality and not being
现实连接，而不是被
inside of your wishes about why can't
自己的愿望束缚，比如“为什么
people be more like this why can't
人们不能更像这样？为什么没有
somebody tell me this why can't they
人告诉我这个？为什么他们不能
give me this why can't I be successful
给我这个？为什么我不能成功？”等等等等，这本身就很美好。
blah blah blah blah getting rid of your
摆脱你的
Illusions and just looking at the way
幻想，看看
that life is is sort of I guess would be
生活本来的样子，我想这大概就是
the through through line of all of my
我所有
books do you see Life as a bit of a game
书的主线。你认为人生有点像一场游戏吗？
and is that a healthier way to view Life
这种看待人生的方式更健康吗？一场
a game where we need to learn the rules
我们需要学习规则，
and then play the game versus fight
然后参与游戏的游戏，而不是对抗
game yeah it's all a game um definitely
游戏规则的不公？是的，一切都是一场游戏。嗯，绝对是。嗯，
uh there was a great um uh man on the
左边有一位伟大的……嗯，左派，
named Saul Alinsky who wrote a book
名叫扫罗。 阿林斯基写了一本书，
called Rules for Radicals he was a
叫做《激进分子的规则》。他曾是
strategist for Union organizing and he
工会组织的战略家，他
hated he would hate the world today with
痛恨当今世界，痛恨
people with all of their virtual
人们沉迷于虚拟世界的各种姿态。
signaling and everything he said if you
他说，如果你
want to change life if you believe that
想改变生活，如果你相信
there's Injustice you have to be a
存在不公正，你就必须成为一名
strategist it's Warfare you have to
战略家。这是一场战争，你必须
organize you have to understand the
组织起来，你必须理解那些能够带来
rules that will lead to actual change in
真正改变的规则。
this world and whenever you enter the
当你进入
realm of rules and strategy it is like a
规则和战略的领域时，就像在玩一场
game you know and so yeah I believe that
游戏。所以，是的，我相信那些满脑子
moralistic ideas who think just because
道德观念的人，他们认为只要自己
they believe something is right that it
相信某件事是对的，就能得到
want they're just living in it fools you
想要的一切。他们只是活在自己的世界里，愚蠢至极。你
have to strategize if you don't you're
必须制定战略，否则
just bullshitting you're just pretend
你就是在胡说八道，只是在装腔作势，只是在作秀，
you're just virtue signaling you want
想让
people to see you as a saint if you're
人们把你当成圣人。如果你
not willing to get your hands dirty and
不愿意亲力亲为，不愿意
to organize and to say I've got to take
组织起来，不愿意说“我必须采取
this A B C D I have to figure out the
这些行动，我必须弄清楚如何才能
process of getting there then all you're
达到目标”，那么你
doing is just playing a game of
所做的只是在玩弄权术。
appearances as opposed to the real game
表面上的博弈与真正做事的策略截然不同，
the opposite of that strategy you're
你说的这种策略的反面是什么？
talking about so I'm trying to figure
所以我试图弄清楚，那些
currently not strategizing in their life
目前生活中没有制定策略的普通人，
what are they doing
他们在做什么？
um you know everybody I guess you could
嗯，你知道，我想可以
say everybody has a strategy but their
说每个人都有策略，但他们的
strategies are extremely ineffective
策略极其无效，
their strategies are full of Illusions
充满了幻觉。
so human beings have to strategize
人类必须制定策略，
because to wake up in the morning and to
因为早上醒来，要做
go I've got to make breakfast you got to
早餐，就必须
strategize how you're going to cook and
计划如何烹饪、
what you're going to make and what
做什么、
you're going to do the day and what
一天要做什么以及
wear you know it's human it's Human
穿什么。这是人之常情，是人性使然。
it's just people do it very very badly
只是人们在这方面做得非常糟糕，他们
and they do it badly because they're so
做得糟糕是因为他们太
emotional now I'm not against emotions
情绪化了。我并不反对情绪，
and emotions play a huge role and I'm
情绪扮演着重要的角色，我
writing a lot about it in my new book
在我的新书中也对此进行了很多探讨，
but the ability to get things done you
但要想把事情做好，你
have to be in control of your emotions
必须控制自己的情绪，你必须
you have to take a step back and you
退后一步，你必须告诉自己：
go I'm not going to
我不会再这样下去了。
react this person is pressuring me
这个人给我施加压力，
they're saying these things my natural
他们说了这些话，我的本能反应
tendency is to react get my back up and
是反击，我会反击，但我决定后退一步，思考怎样才能让他们闭嘴，怎样才能
make them get out of my life what's
让他们滚出我的生活，怎样才能摆脱他们，怎样才能
them what's going to defeat them if
打败他们（如果
they're an adversary all right I made
他们是我的对手）。好吧，我决定
that decision not to react to get
不做出反应，不让自己
emotional all right now I have to think
情绪失控。好吧，现在我必须思考，
if I do this they're going to react this
如果我这样做，他们会这样反应；
way but if I surprise them with this
但如果我用这个角度出其不意地攻击他们，他们会
angle they won't know what to do and
不知所措，
then they'll they'll react in a
然后他们的反应就会不
different way and I'll be in control of
一样，我就能掌控局面。
the situation I strategize I go through
我会制定策略，我会
a process of of gaming out the
推演各种
possibilities here and that's to be a
可能性，这就是
strategist the opposite is a book that I
战略家的本质。与此相反的是，我
meant to write after seduction which is
打算在《诱惑》之后写一本书，那是
a book about human
一本关于人类
stupidity to not be strategic is to be
愚蠢的书。不讲策略就是
stupid and and PE stupid stupid people
愚蠢，愚蠢的人比任何人都更愚蠢，
their bad Wars the bad things they lead
他们糟糕的策略和战争比任何人都更糟糕。 坏事会把
people into to their bad politics Etc so
人引向歧途，比如糟糕的政治等等，所以这和
that's the opposite of strategy
战略
stupidity I also heard within there that
愚蠢正好相反。我还听说，
sort of emotion being emotionally driven
情绪化、受情绪驱动会
is very much it doesn't allow you to
严重阻碍你制定
have effective strategies because you'll
有效的策略，因为你会陷入
in yeah you'll get personal things
其中，你会纠结于一些无关紧要的事情。
rise above though I think we all want to
虽然我们都想
master that I would love to master the
掌握这种能力，但我希望能
ability to rise above in all situations
在任何情况下都能超越这些情绪。
times well you can when you're younger
年轻的时候比较难，
it's harder because because you've got
因为
your hormones you've got all that energy
荷尔蒙分泌旺盛，精力充沛，肾上腺素飙升，所以更难做到。年纪大了就容易一些。
you have a A system that you use just to
你有没有一套方法让
detach yourself from the emotion
自己摆脱情绪的困扰？
sometimes well I'm not always good at it
我并不总是很擅长。
um so I've learned to not react
所以我学会了，
emotionally when people say something
当别人说一些我
that I think is going to be
觉得会
triggering I just don't do anything I go
触动我的话时，我不做出任何情绪反应。我什么也不做，
into my zen mode
进入禅定状态。
oh it's just it's just life it's just
哦，这只是生活，这只是
words it's just verbiage doesn't matter
言语，这只是文字，无关紧要。
it doesn't mean anything to me I'm
这对我来说毫无意义，我保持
neutral I'm unaffected I'm in my Citadel
中立，不受影响，我安然无恙。再见，
goodbye fine it's okay if I get angry
没关系。就算我生气了，
and I write that email which I still do
写了那封邮件（我现在还是会写），我也
I don't send it I put it in my draft box
不会发，我会把它放到草稿箱里，过
I look at it a week L what the [__] was
一个星期再看。
I thinking about I'm glad you didn't
我当时到底在想什么？幸好你没
send that you know you delay your
发。你知道，你会延迟
reactions but mostly I've trained myself
反应，但我主要是训练自己，
and I must say my meditation practic has
而且我必须说，我的冥想练习
helped me to not react when people say
帮助我控制情绪，当别人说一些让我恼火的话时，我不会做出过激反应。
get under my skin I just go that's them
我会告诉自己：那是他们，
it's not me they're another human being
不是我。他们也是人，
they have a bad idea I don't care it's
他们只是有个糟糕的想法，我不在乎。这
not my bad idea it's their life as you
不是我的糟糕想法，这是他们的人生。你
know whoop are a sponsor of this podcast
知道，Whoop是这个播客的赞助商，
and I'm an investor in the company and
我也是这家公司的投资人。
last month I had the chance to sit down
上个月，我有机会
with Kristen Holmes she's a VP of
和Whoop的绩效副总裁Kristen Holmes坐下来聊了聊。
much from our conversation about
从我们的谈话中，我学到了很多关于
circadian rhythms and things like sleep
昼夜节律的知识，比如睡眠
study show that for every 45 minutes of
研究表明，每45分钟的
sleep debt that you acrew that your
睡眠不足…… 我相信，睡眠不足会导致你的
decision-making ability will drop by up
决策能力下降高达
to 10% and when you're chronically
10%，而当你长期睡眠
underslept you'll only be a fraction of
不足时，你只能发挥出你全部的潜能，成为
partner friend manager that you can be
你作为老板、合作伙伴、朋友、管理者所能达到的水平。这就是
that's why I'm obsessed with whoop which
为什么我如此痴迷于 Whoop，它
not just tracks but coaches you on how
不仅可以追踪你的睡眠，还能指导你如何
to get better at sleep so you can bring
改善睡眠，让你在所做的
your best to everything that you choose
每一件事中都发挥出最佳状态。
to do if you're not convinced you can
如果你还不相信，你可以
risk-free with zero commitment just by
免费试用 Whoop 30 天，完全无风险，无需任何承诺，只需
going to join. whoop.com
前往加入即可。  whoop.com 的
CEO that's join. woop.com
CEO 加入了。  woop.com 的
CEO and let me know how you get on if
CEO，如果你不喜欢，请告诉我你的感受，
join. woop.com
加入没有任何义务。  woop.com 的
CEO earlier you mentioned the opposite
CEO，您之前提到过
of strategy with stupidity so let's talk
愚蠢是战略的反面，所以我们来聊聊
politics it's a really interesting time
政治吧。
in politics at the moment I'm really
目前政治局势非常有趣，我尤其
obsessed with us politics in particular
关注美国政治，
because it's it's more like a reality
因为这边的政治更像真人秀，而
show over here than um in the UK it's
英国的政治则
quite boring it is very boring over
相当无聊。
there I must admit this year Trump is
我必须承认，今年特朗普要和
running for re-election against Biden
拜登竞选连任，
the country seems to be very divided for
美国似乎因为各种原因而严重分裂。
a number of different reasons it feels I
感觉，我
don't know I just feel like it's more
不知道该怎么说，就是感觉比以往任何时候都更加
divided than ever I do feel like the
分裂。我觉得
left has moved further left than ever
左翼比以往任何时候都更加左倾，以至于我
before to the point that I I struggled
很难与他们产生
to resonate with that side and I still
共鸣，而且我仍然
don't resonate with the the right so I
无法与右翼产生共鸣，所以我
kind of feel a bit trapped what what do
感觉有点进退两难。
you think of everything that's going on
您对目前发生的一切有什么看法？
and how does your kind of work in form
您是如何看待正在
what's happening
发生的事情
and everything in between well U we all
以及介于两者之间的一切的？
have biases and um I've come from more
嗯，我们都有偏见，我来自更偏向
of the the liberal side the left side uh
自由主义的左翼阵营，
I was actually rather extreme when I was
我年轻的时候其实相当极端，
younger so I have that bias um so I'm
所以我有这种偏见。 我
not really going to be objective so
其实不太想客观，所以先说明这一点。
let's get that out of the way right you
你
know I have my emotional reactions my
知道，我
triggering by what I see but um I'm very
看到的东西会引发我的情绪反应，但我非常
concerned about the overall Spirit the
关注整体的精神面貌，也就是时代精神。
so I worked as um I know this will sound
我之前在一家上市公司American Apparel的董事会工作，我知道这听起来
like I'm going in in a tangent but bear
像是在跑题，但请听我慢慢道来。
Apparel and I was brought on there
我之所以被招进去，是
because I was friends with the CEO but
因为我和CEO是朋友，但
he thought of me as a strategist because
他觉得我是个战略家，因为
he loved the 48 Laws of Power and I
他很喜欢《权力的48条法则》。我
started Ed seeing that things were kind
开始意识到公司的情况正在
downhill and I sort of had my finger on
走下坡路，我大概也明白问题出在哪里。
what the problem was the problem was our
问题在于，
our demographic was basically young
我们的目标客户主要是
women at the ages 18 to
18到24岁的年轻女性，
24 it's a very difficult demographic to
这是一个很难
deal with because their tastes change
驾​​驭的群体，因为她们的品味变化
very quickly they're very viral etc etc
很快，很容易被各种潮流吸引等等。American
American Apparel it was sudden slowly
Apparel早期的成功模式很快就
becoming a
变得
cliche right and it wasn't going to
老套，无法
translate well to a new generation
很好地吸引新一代，也
coming up which ended up being gen Z so
就是Z世代。所以
I had the idea of like we need to have
我…… 我向CEO提出了一个想法，那就是我们需要举办
these Retreats these yearly things where
这些年度研讨会，让
we step back from the day-to-day
我们从日常
business and we think about the brand
业务中抽身出来，思考品牌的发展方向、未来的发展趋势以及我们将如何适应
adapt we're not going to change it but
变化
we're going to adapt etc etc I presented
等等。我
to
向
CEO no we don't need anyah what I came
CEO汇报了这个想法，但他拒绝了。我的最终结论是，
are so awful large businesses why they
大型企业之所以如此糟糕，为何
suck why they're never successful why
总是失败，为何总是
they're so damn
令人
annoying is because they're always
厌烦，是因为它们总是忙于
dealing with the quarterly report at
季度报告，
least for publicly traded businesses
至少对于上市公司而言是如此。
right they can't have a long-term Vision
它们无法制定长远的愿景，
because they can't afford it they have
因为它们负担不起。它们必须
to deal with what Wall Street will say
应对华尔街
to that quarterly report and and you
对季度报告的反应，以及
know what what what what the investors
投资者的反应。
are how they're going to react to sit
坐下来，冷静思考一
where you're going to be in a year or
两年后的发展方向，
two we might not even exist in a year or
我们甚至可能在一两年后就不复存在了，
two so forget it well politics is the
所以别想了。政治也是如此，
same thing you've got to win elections
你必须赢得选举，
you're facing every couple of years
每隔几年或
every four years you don't have the
四年就要面临一次选举，你没有时间去
luxury of thinking of the larger picture
思考未来。 更宏观的层面，
and that's what we're suffering from
这就是我们
right now because if you look at the
现在面临的困境。如果你看看
America nobody has any loyalty to
美国的政治局势，就会发现没有人对任何事物忠诚。
anything so in my age when I grew up you
在我成长的年代，如果你
were a Democrat you were a Republican
是民主党人，或者共和党人，
and you had kind of roots and you
你就会找到归属感，并对此
believed in that because well the
深信不疑。因为
Democratic party was for the working
民主党代表工人阶级，代表工会，代表
the common guy the little guy the FDR
普通民众，代表小人物，秉持着罗斯福、
mentality even to some extent Kennedy
肯尼迪
and Johnson the Republicans we were for
和约翰逊的理念；而共和党则代表
big business for lower taxes blah blah
大企业，代表低税收等等。你会对它产生
blah you had a sense of connection to it
一种归属感。
now people have no connection at all to
现在，人们对
any particular party which is fine I
任何政党都没有丝毫归属感，这当然无可厚非，我也不例外。
don't I don't but what that means is
但这也就意味着政治局势
it's so volatile so somebody will vote
极不稳定。有人会投票
for Obama then they'll vote for Trump
给奥巴马，然后又会投票给特朗普，
then they'll vote for Biden and then
接着又会投票给拜登，之后又会
they'll vote for Trump again and there
再次投票给特朗普。
are plenty of people in that situation
很多人都处于这种状态，
they have no roots they're not connected
他们没有归属感，与任何事物都没有联系。这
to anything and it's not people's fault
不是人们的错，
it's our politics fault they're not
而是我们政治的错。政治没有
creating a sense of what it means to be
塑造出
an American what is it can you give us a
美国人的身份认同感。那么，美国人的身份认同感究竟是什么呢？你能赋予它什么？ 给我们一个关于
American in 2024 that will connect us
2024年美国人身份认同的故事，一个神话，它将把我们联系在一起，让
that will kind of give us a sense of
我们感受到
what is beautiful about our country
我们国家的美好之处，
because there are beautiful things about
因为我们的国家确实有很多美好的东西。
create that kind of a vision if you can
如果你能
step back and you can think in longer
退后一步，从长远的
term all right maybe it's hard to do
角度思考，创造这样的愿景是完全有可能的。好吧，也许对美国来说很难做到
that for America but what is it for the
这一点，但对
goddamn Democratic party what does it
该死的民主党来说又意味着什么呢？成为一名
mean to be a Democrat what does it mean
民主党人意味着什么？
to be now to be a Republican it just
现在成为一名共和党人又意味着什么？仅仅
means to be a lap dog for Donald Trump
意味着成为唐纳德·特朗普的走狗，
to believe everything he does but the
相信他所做的一切。但
Democrats have their own problems their
民主党也有他们自己的问题，他们
own issues it doesn't you can't have a
自己的困境。你不能有一个
party that's just against everything
只反对一切的政党。
what are you for I often tell people I'm
你支持什么？我经常告诉人们，我
sick of hearing what you hate I'm sick
厌倦了听你抱怨什么，我厌倦了听
of hearing what you're against I'm sick
你反对什么，我厌倦了
of hearing what you're complaining tell
听你抱怨什么。告诉
me what you want tell me what you're for
我你想要什么，告诉我你支持什么，
tell me your vision of what a great
告诉我你对一个伟大
country would be like but you can't they
国家的愿景。但你做不到，他们做不到，
can't do that because they're only in
因为他们只存在于这个圈子里。
this bubble of what I hate what I'm
我讨厌什么，我
against what I'm trying to protect etc
反对什么，我试图保护什么
etc so there's got to be a a politician
等等，这些都像一个泡沫。所以，总有一天会出现一位政治家，他
that rises up at some point that has a
有
vision that's not just a demagogue
远见卓识，他不是只会煽动民粹、只会展现个人
that's not just a charismatic that's
魅力、只顾
looking out for themsel they can connect
自己的人。他能把所有
the dots that can say this is what it
点连接起来，说出“这就是
means to be in this party this is our
加入这个党的意义，这就是我们的
vision this is what connects this is the
愿景，这就是我们之间的纽带，这就是粘合剂”。
separate parts of it okay but we're the
没错，党内会有各种不同的部分，但我们是
party of the of the work
工人阶级的党，对吧？我们是
to protect people protect make life
保护人民、让
easier for them or we're the party of
他们生活更轻松的党，或者我们是商业的党
business etc etc I don't care what it is
等等。我不在乎是什么，
but create a vision a sense of who you
但要创造一个愿景，一种关于你
are of what it connects to hit people in
是谁、它与什么相连的意识，从而触动人们的
their heart in their you see Trump
内心。你看，特朗普之所以
succeeds because he has an emotional
成功，是因为他能
visceral effect on people and he's very
对人们产生强烈的情感冲击，而且他非常
good at it the Democrats can't learn
擅长这一点。民主党人却学不会这一点，他们
that it's all always about a laundry
总是列出一长串“
list of we're going to do a b c d and e
我们要做什么”的清单。
we're going to hit the numbers we're
达到目标，我们要
going to reduce inflation we're to get
降低通货膨胀，我们要
create this amount of jobs Etc it's all
创造一定数量的就业岗位等等，这一切都只是
in the head it's not in here you've got
想法，并非真的存在。你必须
to create you got to connect to people
创造，你必须与人们建立起
viscerally emotionally you have to
发自内心的情感联系，你必须
create a myth that will connect people
创造一个神话，将人们联系起来，即使是在
even within their disperate little
他们各自分散的
niches and it's possible because to
小圈子里。这是可能的，因为
believe it's impossible goes against the
认为这是不可能的违背了
grain of History somebody will emerge I
历史的规律。总会有人出现——
might be dead when it happens who will
也许到那时我已经不在人世了——他会
go through that some process by that
经历这个过程，
because otherwise everything will fall
否则一切都会
apart Robert we have a closing tradition
崩溃。罗伯特，我们这个播客有个结束的传统，上
on this podcast where the last guest
一位嘉宾
leaves a question for the next guest oh
会给下一位嘉宾留一个问题。哦，
I remember not I I didn't prepare it's
我记得，不，我没准备。
okay I'm sure I'm sure you can come up
没关系，我相信，我相信你能
with one about the sublime maybe I don't
想出一个关于崇高的问题。也许吧，我不
know we'll
知道，我们
see the question for you
拭目以待。给你的问题
is okay and you're not allowed to say
好了，你不能什么都不说。
nothing if you could change one thing
如果你可以改变过去十年中的一件事，那会是什么？
why well um I would have I would have
为什么？嗯，我会……我会
prevented my
阻止我的
stroke um I would have uh realized that
中风。嗯，我会……意识到
I was burning myself out writing the law
我写《人类法则》时把自己累垮了。 如果是我，
of human nature I would have taken it
我会
slower I would have realized that my
放慢速度，我会意识到我的
body has limits and I would have uh I
身体有极限，我会对
would have been easier on myself and not
自己宽容一些，不会让自己承受那么大的压力。
put myself CU that book was very
那本书
stressful and very difficult I would
压力很大，也很难写，我会
have taken it slower I would have gone
放慢
pace and I wouldn't have had my stroke
速度，换个节奏，就不会中风了，
and I'd be so much
我会
happier do you think you could have pre
快乐得多。你觉得你能
prevented your strike yeah definitely I
预防中风吗？当然可以。我的
mean
意思是，
circumstances um but the stress of
情况很特殊，
writing the human nature kind of ground
写《人性》的压力让
ground me down and then I had kind of
我精疲力竭，而且我本来就有
high blood pressure already and then I
高血压。后来我
took a trip to New York where I forgot
去纽约旅行，忘了带
my blood pressure medication and then I
降压药，然后
was hiking in a park and a wasp stung me
在公园徒步的时候被黄蜂蛰了。
here and 5 days later this whole area
五天后，整个被蛰的地方都
got inflamed turned red I was itching I
红肿发炎，痒得难受，我
couldn't stand it went to the doctor
去看医生，医生给
they prescribed me basically a steroid
我开了类固醇，结果
which raised my blood pressure to the
血压飙升。
roof and then when I had the stroke my
后来我中风的时候，
blood clot was exactly where that wasp
血栓正好长在
sting was in my neck so if I hadn't worn
脖子上被黄蜂蛰的地方。所以，如果我没有把
myself into the ground if I hadn't
自己累垮，如果我…… 如果我没
forgotten my blood pressure medication
忘记吃降压药，
if I hadn't if that doctor hadn't
如果那个医生没给
prescribed to me that nasty pronone if I
我开那种难吃的药，如果我当时
had just been more careful like that I
更小心点，我
probably wouldn't have had
可能就不会
stroke are you able to forgive that
中风了。你能原谅那
sequence of events and the people
一系列事件和
involved yeah I have to I forgiven the
相关的人吗？是的，我必须原谅。我原谅了那只
WASP you know
黄蜂。你知道，
that wasp maybe died because of me
那只黄蜂可能因为我而死，
because I don't know if wasps die when
因为我不知道黄蜂蜇人后会不会死，
they sting you bees do but I forgiven
蜜蜂会。但我原谅了那只
the WASP um I've walked past that spot
黄蜂。我走过
where the wasp stung me and given my
黄蜂蜇我的地方，默默地为
little prayer to it and said I'm sorry
它祈祷，说对不起，
about your little life Etc and yeah I've
你的生命就这样结束了。是的，
I've forgiven uh I I've gotten over that
我已经原谅了，我已经释怀了，我已经接受了这件事。
and I've made my peace with it you know
你知道吗？这是命中注定的，是
happen aor fatti it was my fate and
我的命运，而且很可能
probably probably it happened for a good
它的发生是有
reason I mean I'm right now
原因的。我的意思是，我现在的
contradicting my answer to that person's
回答和之前那个人的
question but so was so life
问题自相矛盾，但人生就是如此。
because the way I think about it is I
因为我的想法是，我当时有点
Reckless with what I thought I could do
鲁莽，以为自己能做到什么。 确实，
and probably if I hadn't had my stroke I
如果我没中风，
probably would have something else bad
可能还会发生其他更糟糕的事情，
would have happened because I I didn't
因为我没有
realize my physical limits I probably
意识到自己的身体极限。
would have and so I'm alive I have my
所以我还活着，我的
brain and I'm writing this next book
大脑还在，我正在写下一本书。
so it happened for a reason if that bee
所以这一切的发生是有原因的。如果那天那只蜜蜂（黄蜂）
wasn't there that day wasp sorry
不在那里……抱歉，
correction if that was no no preas
更正一下，如果
please if that wasp wasn't there that
那天那只黄蜂不在那里……
day and I say this because I've been
我说这些是因为我
reading a few books recently about how
最近读了一些书，讲的是
throughout human history these tiny
纵观人类历史，
little events like the Nagasaki where
像长崎原子弹爆炸这样的小事件，
they dropped the bombs and all of these
以及所有这些
tiny little events with a a cloud that
小事件，比如一朵
flew over a butterfly effect all of the
飞过的云，都可能引发蝴蝶效应。所有
anything from the how these tiny
这些
seemingly insignificant chance events
看似微不足道的偶然事件，是如何
can have massive consequences you're
造成巨大后果的？你这话要是
going to make me cry cuz what if there
让我哭出来了，如果当时有
was like a little bit of wind and the
一点风，
WASP didn't come directly in my
黄蜂没有直接飞到我
path yeah I know it's horrifying but is
面前呢？我知道这很可怕，但这就是
the world we live
我们所处世界的本质吗？
in we tiny little things that we cannot
我们无法
predict can determine our lives in huge
预测的小事，却能以巨大的方式决定我们的人生。 它
ways can sway our lives in huge ways is
会以巨大的方式影响我们的生活，
there any anything that we can do about
我们对此能做些什么吗？
it no there's nothing you can do about
不，你对此无能为力。
it you you know it's it's it's Ryan
你知道，这是瑞恩·
holiday we'll talk to you about it you
霍利迪，我们会和你谈谈的。
what you can do is the stoic philosophy
你能做的就是斯多葛哲学，它关注的
is how you react to it mentally you
是你如何从心理上应对它。你
can't change the physical circumstance
无法改变物质环境，
but you can change how you think about
但你可以改变你
it and how you
对它的看法和
react Robert thank you so much for your
反应。罗伯特，非常感谢你抽出
time and your wisdom and I'm so very
时间分享你的智慧，我非常非常
very excited for your upcoming book
期待你的新书，
because if it's anything like your past
因为它和你之前的
books it's really something worth
作品一样，真的值得
waiting for and that's nice to hear
期待。很高兴听到你这么说，
thank you before we started recording
谢谢。在我们开始录音之前，
you told me about the process you've
你跟我讲了
going through You' spent four years
你的创作过程。你花了四年时间
writing this upcoming book Sublime so
写这本即将出版的书《崇高》，
far it's been four and a half and it'll
到目前为止已经四年半了，还需要
be another year and a half so that'll be
一年半，所以总共是
six total years yes pouring I it's so
六年。是的，倾注心血，这太
incredibly it's so inspiring to me well
不可思议了，太鼓舞人心了。
keep this in mind Stephen I can't
斯蒂芬，记住这一点，我不会
type so um my I used to be a fast typist
打字，所以……我以前打字很快，但是…… 我
and I can't go up take a hike to clear
不能去徒步旅行来清醒
my head so everything it's not like
头脑，所以所有事情都不像以前那样
double takes like it's like one and a
轻松，而是要花上一倍
half times more I have to write things
半的时间。我必须手写，必须手改，必须
have to dictate into the computer I have
口述到电脑里，必须
to edit with one hand I have to clear my
单手编辑。我必须在
mind without hiking so everything takes
不能徒步旅行的情况下清醒头脑，所以所有事情都要花上
one and a half times more that's
一倍半的时间。这
like a four or five year book but as you
本书可能要花四五年才能完成，但就像你
said about your cycle when you slow
说的，当你放慢节奏时，
things down sometimes you enjoy them
有时你会
more and you make better things yes I
更享受其中，也能创作出更好的作品。是的，我
think you're right and and probably the
想你是对的，
slower cooking will make a better book
慢工出细活或许能成就一本更好的书。
exactly right I can't wait I hope
没错，我迫不及待了。我希望
everyone has your existing books cuz
每个人都有你之前的作品，因为
they're all um as everyone's witnessed
它们都……正如大家
today they're all based
今天所看到的，它们都基于具
on challenging but important enduring
有挑战性但又至关重要的永恒
wisdom every single one of them and I
智慧，每一本书都是如此。我
think we need more challenging wisdom in
认为当今社会需要更多这样的挑战性智慧。非常
thank you so much Robert you're a real
感谢你，罗伯特，你真是……不客气，你
um you're welcome hero to many thank you
是许多人的英雄。
so much okay thank you stev thank you
非常感谢。好的，谢谢你，史蒂夫，谢谢你
for inviting me back
再次邀请我。
[Music]
[音乐]
oh
哦